字幕来源：Shooter
BD版本校订：Tears
地方法院
你做的很好，非常好
漫长复杂的审理程序已经结束 这是一宗一级谋杀案
预谋杀人在刑事诉讼中 是刑责最重的罪名
你们都已经听过证词 也明明白法律条文的规定
现在你们必须坐下来 好好地厘清这宗案子的真伪
在本案中已有一人身亡 另一个人的生死掌握在你们手上
如果你们能提出合理的怀疑 无法确认被告是否有罪...
基于这个合理的怀疑 你们必须做出无罪的判决
如果你们找不出合理的怀疑 你们必须基于良知...
判决被告有罪
然而你们的决定必须一致
如果你们裁定被告有罪 本庭将会对他施以严厉的惩罚
最高的刑罚会是死刑
这是一项沉重的责任 谢谢各位
后备陪审员可以离去
陪审团请退下
12怒汉
要来块口香糖吗？
- 我不要，谢谢 - 这扇窗户卡住了
快来帮帮我 好了
你知道吗？ 我打电话问过气象局
今天将是今年中最热的一天
- 我还以为这里有空调 - 先生，请问尊姓大名？
- 就是那个 - 谢谢你
好了，各位，大家都到了
如果你们需要别的东西 我就在外面，尽管叫我
我不知道他们会锁上门
他们当然会锁门 你以为他们会怎么做？
我不知道 我只是从来没想过会有这种事
- 那是什么东西？ - 我还以为我们要投票表决
好主意 或许我们该选他当参议员
- 你觉得如何？ - 我不知道，挺有趣的
是吗？我差点就睡着了
- 我从来没有当过陪审员 - 是吗？我有很多次的经验
律师们说的话让我很火大 凶手是谁真的是太明显了
- 你听过这么多无聊的话吗？ - 那是他们的工作
一点都没错，这就是司法系统
我觉得现在孩子得吃点苦头 才不敢惹麻烦
这能帮我们省下时间跟金钱
- 开始裁决吧 - 好主意
大家动作快一点 我们还有很多工作要做
先等一下 还有一个人在洗手间里
- 我们照常规坐吗？ - 我不知道，应该是吧
你坐到我的位置了
- 对不起 - 没关系
这里的风景还不错吧
你对这个案子有什么看法？
我觉得很有趣，一点都不无聊 你瞭解我的意思吧
能遇上谋杀案算我们运气好
我还以为我们会遇上伤害案 或窃盗案，那真的很无聊
- 那是伍尔沃斯大楼吗？ - 没错
我从小到大都住在纽约 却从来没有去过那里
你们得抽丝剥茧地把案情弄清楚 就跟电影上演的一样
对，关于凶刀 又是怎么一回事呢？
他们竟要我们这些成年人 去相信那种胡言乱语
- 我早就知道事情会变成这样 - 你说的对
你的鼻子通了，现在来看看 你的眼睛吧，你感冒了吗？
因为太热引起的感冒真是要人命 我只要一摸鼻子就会觉得很痛
我真的瞭解，我感冒才刚好
- 快点，团长先生，要开始了 - 那家伙还在洗手间里
有什么消息吗？ 我还没有空看文件
- 不知道今天的股市指数是多少？ - 你是做股票的？
我是股票经纪人
我开了一间传呼公司 叫做贝克传呼公司
公司名字是我太太取的 我白手起家，现在雇了37个人
好了，大家快坐下
好了，我们可以很快离开这里 我已经买好今晚的球赛门票
是洋基队对克利夫兰队的比赛
本案的被告是摩杰路斯基 这孩子简直无药可救
他应该被关进牢里，你知道吗？
你真的很喜欢看棒球，对吧？
我们要坐在哪里？
我想我们得依照 陪审员的编号坐下
一、二、三，以此类推 沿着桌子坐下，希望大家别介意
- 那有什么差别呢？ - 听起来挺合理的
- 就这么办吧 - 十二号要坐在你的右手边吗？
- 对，沿着顺时钟方向坐下 - 从你开始，一、二....
你对检察官的印象如何？
你说什么？
我觉得他很尖锐 像连珠炮似地提出问题...
但前后顺序相当有逻辑 让我留下了深刻的印象
- 我觉得他非常专业 - 也非常有冲劲
- 大夥们，请安静 - 没问题
我们就要开始了 站在窗户旁边的先生
- 我们就要开始了 - 对不起
这真的很难懂，对吧？ 那孩子杀了他的父亲
听我说，这种事常发生
养子不教父之过 或许那是他活该
- 大家都到了吗？ - 那老头还在洗手间里
- 麻烦你去叫他过来好吗？ - 没问题
- 你是洋基队的球迷吗？ - 不，我支持巴尔的摩队
巴尔的摩队？
那就像是每天 头都会被铁橇敲上一记
除了他们的外野手还不错之外 他们有什么厉害的？
我们要开始了
对不起 我不是故意要你们等我
巴尔的摩队！
好了，各位 请注意听我说
你们想要怎么做都可以 我不打算制定任何规则
我们可以先进行讨论再来表决 那是一种可行的方法
当然啰 我们也可以立刻进行表决
我想依照惯例 我们得先进行假投票
我们来投票吧，谁知道呢 或许我们可以立刻离开这里
好吧，大家都知道 这是一宗一级谋杀案...
如果我们裁决被告有罪 那等于是送他坐上电椅
- 那是必然的结果 - 我们知道
- 好了，现在来表决吧 - 有人反对进行表决吗？
我没意见
记住，不论如何 我们都得达成共识，那是规定
大家都准备好了吗？ 认为他“有罪”的人请举手
一、二、三、四 五、六、七...
八、九、十、十一 十一个人认为他有罪
认为他“无罪”的人请举手
一票，好吧 十一票有罪，一票无罪
- 至少现在我们有结论了 - 天啊，总是会出现唱反调的人
我们现在该怎么办呢？
- 我猜我们得好好讨论一下 - 天啊
你真的觉得他是无辜的？
- 我不知道 - 你跟我们一样坐在法庭里
你应该可以看得出来 那孩子是个危险的杀手
- 他才十八岁 - 他已经够大了
他拿刀子往他父亲的胸口戳去 把他给杀了
在法庭上他们不断证明了这一点 你要我一一跟你说明吗？
不必了
- 你到底想怎么样？ - 我只是想谈一谈
你想谈什么？十一票“有罪” 除了你，大家都达成了共识
我想问你 你真的相信他的说词？
- 我不知道，或许我不相信 - 你为什么会认为他“无罪”？
十一个人都认为他“有罪” 我真的很难举起手...
送这个孩子坐电椅 完全不去讨论这件事
- 谁说这很容易了？ - 没人
你以为我是胡乱举手的吗？ 我真的觉得那孩子有罪
就算谈上一百年 也无法改变我的想法
我不想改变你 但这个判决攸关一条人命
假设我们错了呢
假设这栋房子会倒塌 什么事都是有可能的
一点都没错
要花多少时间又有什么差别 或许我们花五分钟就能解决此事
我们可以花一小时来讨论 球赛八点才会开始
- 谁有意见？ - 如果只有一小时应该没关系
- 太棒了，我已经听过所有说法- -  - 那不是我们坐在这里的原因
好吧，请你告诉我 我们为什么要坐在这里？
我不知道，或许那是没有原因的 这孩子老是被踢来踢去
他在贫民窟出生 九岁时母亲就过世了
他在孤儿院待过一年半 当时他父亲因为伪造文书罪入狱
他是先天不良，他是个 充满愤怒的野孩子，为什么？
因为每天都会有人打他
他过了悲惨的十八年 我觉得我们该给他一个机会
我们什么都不欠他 他得到公平的审判了，不是吗？
你觉得那场审判要花掉多少钱 他有这样的机会就已经够幸运了
听着，大家都是成年人 我们都听到了实际经过，对吧？
我们不该相信那孩子的说法 我们都知道他是什么样的人
我跟那样的人生活过，你不能相信 他们说的话，你知道的
- 他们一生下来就是骗子 - 只有无知的人才会相信那些话
- 听我说 - 你天生就...
相信真理吗？ 有足够的证据能证明他的罪行
- 我们不需要听你训话 - 我们还有工作要做，快开始吧
这是爆米花，我的公司 负责推销这种产品
“天生充满活力的早餐” 这句广告词是我写的
- 真的很传神 - 没错
- 请安静 - 对不起
随手涂鸭反而能让我沉淀思绪
我们还有事要做 没有必要把时间耗在这里
好吧，坐在那边的先生 不同意我们的看法...
如果你可以告诉我们为什么 或许我们能告诉你你哪里弄错了
这方法挺不错的 我并没有想太多，但....
似乎我们得说服他 他错了，我们才是对的
或许我们该花几分钟的时间 好好地- - ，那只是我的提议
不，你的提议很棒 我们照顺序一一发言吧
从你先来
这真的很难说出个为什么 我就是觉得他有罪
从证词来看一切非常明显 没有人能证明他无罪
也没有人该那么做 该证明他无罪的人是检察官
被告不必发言 那是宪法规定的权利
我知道，但我的意思是- -
我就是觉得他有罪 有目击者看到他杀人
好了，这就是我的想法 对本案我并没有个人偏见...
我只是想讨论事实
首先：
住在凶案现场 楼下的那个老人
在凶案发生当晚的十二点十分 他听到类似发生争执的吵闹声
他听到那个孩子大叫着 “我要杀了你”
一秒钟后他听见有人摔倒的声音
于是他跑到门口 看到那孩子冲下楼梯离开
他打电话报警 警方发现死者胸口插了一把刀
法医推测死亡时间 大约是午夜
这些都是事实，你无法反驳事实 那孩子有罪
我跟其他人一样有同情心 我知道那孩子只有十八岁
- 但他还是得付出代价 - 我同意你的说法
好了，你说完了吗？
- 我说完了 - 下一位
很明显地那孩子的说词 根本都是在瞎编
他说案发时他在看电影...
但他完全想不起来 那部电影跟演员们的名字
- 没错 - 没有人看到他进出电影院
住在对街的那个女人 所做出的证词呢？
- 她看到他杀人 - 好了，请大家照顺序来
等一下，案发时这个女人 躺在床上，她睡不着
她热到受不了，你明白吧？
她从窗户往外看，看到那孩子 将刀子插进他父亲的胸口
时间是十二点十分，完全吻合 她是看着那孩子长大的
他家跟她家只隔了一条电车轨道 她目睹他杀人的经过
当时刚好 有一列电车经过
这辆电车上没有乘客 它是要开到市区去的
当时车上的灯光全暗
律师证明了透过电车车窗 的确可以看到东西...
只要灯光是暗的 你可以看到另一边的景象
我想问你一个问题
你不相信那孩子，为什么会相信 这个女人呢？她跟他是一样的
- 你以为自己很聪明，对吧？ - 各位
- 好了，坐下吧 - 他有什么好得意的？
好了，我们不是来吵架的 现在轮到谁了？
轮到他了，他是五号
我可以弃权吗？
那是你的权利 下一位
我不知道，打从一开始 我就相信他有罪
我一直在寻找他的犯罪动机
这真的很重要，没有犯罪动机 案子就无法成立
住在那孩子家对面的人 在法庭上做出的证词...
非常有力
何况他们提到 死者跟他儿子...
约七点时曾发生过争吵 或许我错了，但我- -
- 是八点才对 - 没错
他们听到了争吵声 却听不清楚到底发生了什么事
他们听到死者 打了他儿子两下
他们看到那孩子愤怒地冲出家门 那能证明什么呢？
那无法证明任何事 那只是事实的一部份
你说那证明了凶手有杀人动机 但我觉得这样的动机不够强烈
这孩子常常被打 暴力对他来说是司空见惯的事
我不觉得被打了两个耳光 就足以让他气到去杀人
或许他真的被逼到受不了 每个人都有极限
你还有话要说吗？
- 没有了 - 好吧，你呢？
我不知道，话都被他们说完了
我们可以一直耗下去 结论还是一样的
这个孩子真的杀了人
看看他的记录
他十岁就进了少年法庭 因为他对老师丢石头
十五岁时进感化院 因为他偷了一部车子
他曾因抢劫被捕
还曾因持刀械斗被抓过两次 他的确是个用刀高手
他的确是个好孩子
从五岁开始 他老爸就会对他饱以老拳
有那种孩子我也会那么做....
现在的孩子 都是那个样子
我小时候 都会叫我爸爸“父亲大人”
- 现在哪个孩子会那样叫老爸？ - 现在的爸爸也不在乎
- 你有孩子吗？ - 我有三个小孩
我有一个儿子
他今年二十二岁了
他九岁大时 因为打输别人逃之夭夭
我目睹那一幕觉得丢脸丢到家了 我差点没有吐出来
我说“我要让你变成一个男子汉 就算我得磨掉你的小命”
我的确让他变成一个男子汉 他十六岁时我们打了一架
他打中了我的下巴 我儿子非常高大
我两年没有见到他
现在的孩子
总是让父母伤透了心....
- 我们继续吧 - 我想我们忘了真正的重点
他来自破碎家庭，住在贫民窟 关于那一点我们爱莫能助
我们要决定他到底有没有罪 这跟他的成长背景无关
他生于贫民窟，那是犯罪的温床 我们都知道这一点
那不是秘密，来自贫民窟的孩子 出了社会很可能会变成恶棍
- 现在我- -  - 你可以再说一次
来自那种地方的孩子都是垃圾 我不想跟他们被归为同类
听我说 我一直都住在贫民窟里
- 等一下 - 拜托
我小时候在塞满垃圾的 后院里玩耍
- 你还可以在我身上闻到臭味 - 听我说
- 这件事无关私人恩怨 - 我觉得有关
他说的人不是你 别那么敏感
- 我能瞭解那样的感觉 - 好了，大家别吵了
我们只是在浪费时间 现在轮到你了，说吧
我还以为你们想要说服我 那不是你们的原意吗？
- 一点都没错 - 我忘了
是他害得我们被困在这里 我们听听他的说法吧
既然我们已经决定好要这么做 我们应该要坚持下去
- 别孩子气了 - 你是什么意思？“孩子气”
你听不懂我的意思吗？ 孩- 子- 气
我只是想有条不紊地 把事情办完
只要你愿意接下这份工作 我可以把嘴巴闭上
你为什么要那么生气？冷静点
别叫我冷静 快来主持会议
你们看过这种事吗？
- 你觉得很有趣吗？ - 算了吧，那一点都不重要
- 不重要？你来试试看 - 不，大家都不想改变现状
- 你做的非常好，请坐 - 对，你表现的很好
你仍然是会议的主持人
好吧，我们来听听别人的说法
如果你们要我说出我的感觉 我一点都不在意
天啊，我不在乎你做了什么
好吧，我没有任何的至理名言 我知道的事跟你们一样多
根据证词，那孩子是有罪的 或许人真的是他杀的
六天来我坐在法庭上 听到目击者接连不断提出证词
大家的语气都十分肯定 对于这次审判我有很特别的感觉
话不要说的太硬了 我想要提出一些问题
或许它们毫无意义
但我觉得被告 并没有做过完整的交叉讯问
- 他遗漏了一些小细节 - 什么小细节？
律师不提出问题 是因为他们已经知道了答案
也很可能是因为 那个律师是大笨蛋，对吧？
- 那是有可能的 - 听起来你已经见过我大舅子了
我一直让自己 站在那孩子的角度来想
我会去请另一个律师来帮我辩护 这场审判攸关我的生死...
我会希望我的律师反驳 目击者的证词，至少他该试试看
听着，这件凶案 有一个目击证人
还有一个人听到凶案发生过程 事后还看到那孩子冲出屋外...
同时还出现了 间接证据
这个案子有两个证人 如果他们都错了呢？
你是什么意思？ 那不是证人的责任吗？
如果他们错了呢？
他们在坐上证人席前 都发过了誓
他们只是人，人难免会犯错 如果他们都错了呢？
- 不，我不那么认为 - 你真的那么想吗？
没有人可以确定那一点 我们又不是在做科学论证
没错，你说的对
现在来谈正事，插在死者胸口的 摺叠刀又是怎么一回事？
等一下，有人还没有发言
- 我们不该照顺序来吗？ - 大家都会有机会说话，安静
那孩子承认当晚他买了这把刀 又是怎么一回事？我们来谈谈吧
好吧，我们来谈一谈 现在来看看那把凶刀
- 团长先生 - 我们都看过凶刀
- 为什么还要再看一次呢？ - 他有权利要求审视证物
- 麻烦你把凶刀拿过来 - 没问题
凶刀是一项强而有力的证据 你不那么认为吗？
- 你说的一点都没错 - 很好
我们得一样样地 来检视所有的事实
一，那孩子在八点钟离开家里 因为他父亲打了他两巴掌
不，他没说他被“打巴掌” 他说“他被揍”，那是不一样的
他长期受到父亲的殴打
二，他跑到附近的二手货店 买了一把....
- 摺叠刀 - 摺叠刀
这不是一把普通的刀子，刀柄上 刻了漂亮的图案，刀锋与众不同
店主说他的店里只有一把这样的刀子
三，八点四十五分左右 他在酒吧前遇到一些朋友，对吧？
- 你说的对 - 一点都没错
他跟朋友一起聊天 在九点四十五分时离开
在这段时间里 他的朋友看到了摺叠刀
四，他们在法庭指认那把刀子 就是凶手使用的凶刀
五，大约十点时他回到家里
从此原告律师跟被告的说词 开始出现分歧
被告说他在十一点三十分时 出门去看电影...
凌晨三点十分回到家发现 父亲已经死了，他遭到逮捕
他还说逮捕他的两名警官 将他丢下楼梯
那把刀子又是怎么一回事？ 他说刀子从口袋的破洞掉了出去...
约在十一点半到三点十分之间 之后他再也没有看到那把刀子
他根本在说谎，事实非常明显 那孩子没有去看电影
没有人看到他十一点半时离家 电影院里有没有人见过他
他完全不记得 那部电影的名字
真正的事实是 那孩子一直待在家里
他跟父亲发生争执 他杀了父亲，在十二点十分离家
他甚至还把刀子的指纹 擦的一干二净
你说这把刀子 从那孩子口袋的破洞掉出来
有人捡起它，跑到他家 用它杀死他父亲...
只为了测试刀子锐不锐利？
很可能是他的刀子不见了 有人用类似的刀子杀了他父亲
请看看这把刀子
它是一把与众不同的刀子
我从来没有看过这样的刀子 卖出它的店主也那么说
这未免太巧了吧？
- 我的意思是或许就是这么巧 - 我可不那么认为
- 你从哪里弄来那个玩意？ - 这把刀子跟凶刀完全一样
- 你到底在做什么？ - 你去哪里拿到那把刀子？
我昨天晚上出去散步 刚好经过那孩子住的社区
我在离那孩子家两条街远的当铺 买下它，只花了我六块钱
买卖摺叠刀是违法的
- 我犯了法 - 你这招真的是太妙了
那能证明什么，或许还有十把 类似凶刀的刀子，那又怎么样？
- 或许是有 - 那是什么意思？
你找到一把类似的刀子 那是了不起的大发现吗？
我们得相信有人 拿类似的刀子杀了他父亲？
- 机率只有百万分之一 - 那是有可能的
但可能性不是很大
好吧，大家请坐下 我们不必站着说话....
他能找到类似凶刀的刀子 真的是太有趣了
- 哪里很有趣了？ - 我不知道，我就是觉得有趣
我们十一个人 都认为他有罪
你到底想做什么？ 你无法改变我们的想法
就算你坚持到底 他还是会被判有罪
- 或许你说的对 - 你打算要怎么做呢？
- 我们可能一整晚都会耗在这里 - 只是一夜，可是那孩子会没命的
我们为什么不干脆在这里扎营？
去跟那个警察说他可以休息了 我们会在这里耗上一阵子
- 他不该拿这件事开玩笑 - 你要我怎么做？
这跟那把刀子有什么关系？ 有人目睹那孩子杀了自己的父亲
你还需要什么证据？ 我真的不想再听你们废话了
我还要跑三家修车厂 赶快把事情办好离开这里吧
对检察官来说那把刀子很重要 他花了- -
- 他只是个小角色，他懂什么？ - 我们把时间浪费在争吵上
怎么样呢？ 只有你认为他无罪
我要提出一项建议 我们何不再投一次票
我要你们十一个人 以书面的方式来做秘密投票
我弃权，如果你们全都 认为他“有罪”，我会赞同你们
我们可以立刻向法官 提出有罪的判决
但只要有人做出“无罪”的判决 我们就得待在这里把事情弄清楚
- 如果你们愿意，我准备好了 - 让我们再度受苦吧
听起来很公平，大家都同意吗？ 有人反对吗？
- 好了，请帮忙传下去 - 那个时钟准吗？
“有罪”
“无罪”
- 天啊，怎么会这样？ - 又有一个混蛋在搞破坏
好了，是谁干的？我想要知道
对不起，这是秘密投票 大家都说好了
- 如果他不想被公开- -  - 你是什么意思？“秘密”
陪审团室里没有任何秘密 我知道是谁干的
你真的是很厉害
你坐在这里投票认为他“有罪” 那家伙的胡言乱语说动了你...
他认为那孩子不可能杀人 于是你改变了心意
那真的太- -
你为什么不丢些铜板 到他的破碗去呢？
等一下 你不能那样子跟我说话
- 你以为你是什么东西？ - 冷静点
他太激动了，快坐下
我当然很激动，我们要把 一个罪有应得的家伙送上电椅
他满口胡言乱语，我们相信了
少来了
- 你为什么要改变心意？ - 改变心意的人不是他，是我
- 太棒了 - 我就知道
- 你要我告诉你为什么吗？ - 我不想听
- 我想把话说清楚 - 我们非得听这些废话不可吗？
- 他有话想说 - 谢谢你
这位先生一直孤军奋战地 跟我们对抗
他并没有说那孩子无罪 他只是说他无法确定他有罪
要孤军奋战对抗荒谬的言论 并不容易
所以他孤注一掷争取支持 我支持他因为我赞同他的动机
那个孩子或许真的杀了人
但我想听到更多的证词 现在的票数是十比二
- 你没有权利离开- -  - 他不会听你说话
他死都不会听的，我们坐下吧
可以继续了吗？
我觉得我们应该休息一下
有人进了洗手间 我觉得我们应该等他
看来我们真的被困在这里了
那老头会做出那种事 真是令人意想不到
真希望我能想出办法 突破这个困局
你知道吗？在广告界- -  我提过我在广告公司工作吗？
有一些怪人在那里工作
我觉得他们一点都不奇怪 只是他们表达自己的方式很特别
我猜在你那一行 也是一样的吧？
- 你是做哪一行的？ - 我是个钟表匠
真的吗？ 我以为最棒的钟表匠都在欧洲
在公司里 要是遇到这种情形- -
在广告公司里 要是遇到这种情形...
总会有人想出妙点子来 我真的都快笑死了....
那真的很奇怪，他们总是 用一句话来说出自己的心声
总会有个广告业务人员站起来说 好了，我想到一个点子
我们把它升上旗杆 看看会不会有人向它敬礼
虽然挺蠢的，但很好笑
嘿...
我刚刚太激动了一点
我无意要为难大家
还好你不是那一种 会被情绪影响的人
我不知道 那个电扇到底是哪里有问题
- 你是业务员吗？ - 我是建筑师
你知道什么叫做“软性推销”？
你有这个技能，相信我
我用的技巧跟别人不一样
说说笑话，陪客人喝几杯 耍耍小手段，你懂吧？
我懂
抓住他们生活的脉动 那就是我的名言
去年我靠卖橘皮果酱 赚了两万七，成绩还不错
毕竟我卖的 可是橘皮果酱
待在这里能得到什么好处？ 刺激吗？
难不成有人撞到你的头 你到现在还耿耿于怀吗？
- 或许是吧 - 你们全都是不切实际的家伙
老是把自己的快乐 建立在别人的痛苦上
你为什么 要浪费我们的时间？
捐点钱做好事 或许能让你觉得舒服点
这个孩子有罪 那简直是再明显不过了
我们为什么还要继续浪费时间？
吵到最后大家的喉咙都痛了
你被困在这里或是去看球赛 那又有什么差别呢？
没有差别，兄弟 完全没有差别
- 他们还挺不错的，对吧？ - 他们跟其他人都一样
天啊，今天真的是够惨的了 你觉得这样还会继续很久吗？
我不知道
他绝对有罪 全世界没有一个人会怀疑
我们早该做出裁决
我并不介意，这比上班好玩多了
- 你认为他无罪，对吧？ - 我不知道，或许是吧
我不认识你 但我很肯定你从未犯过错
你是在浪费你的时间
如果接受审判的人是你自己呢？
我不想回答假设性的问题
我只是一个上班族 要动脑筋的人是我老板...
但我会试试看的
假设你真的可以 说服我们每一个人...
但那孩子真的拿刀子 杀了他父亲呢？
准备好了吗？
对不起，大帅哥
- 随便挑一个 - 好了，大家坐下吧
看来我们得留在这里吃晚餐
好了，快点来谈正式 谁想第一个发言？
- 我有话要说 - 请说
听着，住在凶案现场楼下的老头 说他听到那孩子大叫着
“我要杀了你” 一秒后他听到有人摔倒的声音
他跑到门口 看到那孩子夺门而出
你们想到了什么呢？
隔了一层天花板 他能听得多清楚呢？
他并非透过天花板听到争吵声 那时窗户是打开的
- 要听清楚对方的声音并不容易 - 他在庭上指认出那孩子的声音
别忘了住在对街的女士 她看到那孩子拿刀刺死他父亲
- 难道对你来说这还不够吗？ - 的确是不够
这简直就是在对牛弹琴
她是透过电车的车窗 看到凶案发生的经过
电车一共有六节车厢，她透过 最后两节车厢目睹凶案经过
她记得所有的细节 那是无庸置疑的证据
你们曾经想过 电车要花多少时间- - ？
这不是在玩游戏
你看到了吗？他胆子真大
- 听我说- -  - 他简直是胆大包天
- 好了，别这样 - 这不是在玩游戏吗？
- 冷静点 - 他以为他是什么东西？
别闹了
你们曾经想过电车要花多少时间 才能完全通过某一点吗？
- 我不知道 - 你觉得呢？
我不知道，或许十到十二秒吧
很不错，其他人呢？
- 他说的有道理 - 我们为什么要玩猜谜游戏？
- 你觉得呢？ - 十秒钟吧
好吧，假设真的是十秒钟 你想表达什么呢？
有六节车厢的电车 要花十秒钟才能通过某一个点
假设那一点就是 发生凶案的房间窗口
在那里一伸手 几乎就可以摸到铁轨
我要问你们一个问题 你们之中有人曾住在铁轨旁边吗？
我刚油漆完一间 可以俯视电车线的公寓
- 那是什么样的感觉呢？ - 你是什么意思？
- 很吵吗？ - 天啊
- 那不重要，因为大家都昏沉沉的 - 我曾经住在电车线附近
只要有电车通过 噪音大到令人难以忍受
- 甚至吵得你无法思考 - 请你说重点
我会的，稍安勿躁
请回想一下两个证人的证词 把它们拼凑在一起
首先是住在 楼下公寓的老人
他听到那孩子说 “我要杀了你”...
一秒后他听到 有人摔倒在地的声音
- 没错 - 第二点...
那女人发誓说 当她从窗户往外看时...
她透过电车最后两节车厢 看到凶案发生的经过
- 你到底想说什么？ - 等一下
我们都同意电车得花十秒钟 才能完全通过某一点
因为她是透过最后两节车厢 看到凶案发生的经过...
我们可以推测出 死者是在电车经过时倒在地上
因此电车经过老人家窗口时 发出轰隆隆的噪音...
过了十秒后 死者倒在地上
他说他听到被告说“我要杀了你”
一秒后听到有人跌在地上...
所以他听到那孩子说话的同时 电车刚好经过他家窗口
- 他不可能听得到 - 他真的听到了
- 你相信他的说法？ - 那孩子是扯着喉咙大叫
当时刚好有电车通过 他不可能认得出那孩子的声音
这是在几秒内发生的事 没有人可以测量的那么准确
我认为能送那孩子上电椅的证词 必须非常准确才行
- 我认为他根本就听不出来 - 或许那么吵他真的听不出来
你在胡说什么？
- 他的确可能会听不清楚 - 他为什么要说谎？
或许他想引起别人的注意
你既然想出这么多理论 把它们卖给报社吧
- 一份稿费是三块钱 - 你为什么要那样子对他说话？
会那样子跟老人说话的人 应该要受到谴责
你得学着去尊敬别人，先生
你敢再那样子跟他说话 我一定会给你好看
好了 你想说什么就说吧
你觉得那个老人 为什么要说谎呢？
我在法庭上 一直盯着他看
他穿的外套 在肩膀的部份裂开了
你们注意到了吗？ 我是说他上法庭却穿成那个样子
他是个穿着破外套的老头子
而且他走上证人席的步伐缓慢
他的左脚一跛一跛的 却努力地想要掩饰它...
因为他觉得自己很丢脸
我认为我比你们任何一个人 都瞭解那个老头子
他是个安静，怯懦 不起眼的老头子...
一辈子无所成
没有人认得他 他的名字也没有上过报
没有人认得他，也不会听他说话
七十五年来 没有人征询过他的意见
各位，默默无闻 是一件令人伤感的事
像他那样的人 会希望别人去询问他的意见
有人会听他说话，询问他的意见 即使只有一次对他来说都很重要
要他放弃这个机会 真的很难- -
你的意思是他说谎 只为了体会当大人物的滋味
不，事实上他不算是说谎
或许他幻想他真的听到那些话 认为凶手就是那个男孩
这个说法太妙了
你怎么编得出这样的故事 你又知道多少呢？
谁想吃喉糖？
- 我不要，谢谢 - 给我一颗吧
我还是不明白 你们为什么会认为他无罪
还有一件事 我想跟你们讨论一下
我们证明了那老头听不到 那孩子说“我要杀了你”
- 你根本没有证明任何事 - 假设他真的听到了
你们有多常说这句话呢？ 应该超过好几千次吧
- 那不代表我们真的要- -  - 你到底想做什么？
他说“我要杀了你” 别告诉我他不是这个意思
任何人像他那样说话 都是认真的
天啊，现在我真的不知道了
几个星期前 我跟一位工作夥伴发生争执
他骂我是白痴 于是我对他破口大骂
他要你们去相信他编的故事
被告放话要杀人，他真的动手了
那孩子如果真的想杀人 他会到处嚷嚷让邻居知道吗？
他太聪明了
聪明？他只是个不学无术的混混一般的 他连英语都说不好
甚至连正确的语法都不会
团长先生，我改变了心意 那个孩子应该是“无罪”
- 你说什么？ - 你都听到了
- 你确定？ - 我非常确定
九比三，有罪那一方占优势
但这还不是最后的结论，对吧
你为什么会相信 这个家伙编出来的故事？
你应该去写侦探小说 你一定可以大赚一票的
连那孩子的律师都知道 他根本没有胜诉的机会
从一开始 他的律师就知道了
天啊，听我说 这个家伙真的很厉害
那孩子请了律师 应该由他来帮他打官司
- 为什么你有那么多的话可说？ - 律师的话并不完全是正确的
- 他是法庭指派的律师 - 那是什么意思？
他很可能 并不想出庭打这场官司...
虽然他真的出庭了 从这个案子他捞不到任何好处
赚不到钱，得不到名声 连胜诉的机会都是微乎其微
对一位年轻律师来说 这不是一个好案子
他得去相信他的客户是无罪的 但他并没有那么做
他当然不会那么做 谁会那么做呢？
或许某人的妈妈 或是某个人....
听我说，现在已经很晚了 别再耗下去了
对不起 我做了一些笔记...
我有一些话 想要告诉你们
我一直非常仔细地 在听证人陈述证词...
看起来这位先生 说的话非常有道理
从法庭上的证词看来 这孩子似乎是有罪
- 如果我们深入去- -  - 少来了
我有一个问题
假设那个孩子 真的杀了人
案发的时间 是十二点十分
他是如何被警方逮捕的呢？
他是在三点左右 回到家里...
在家里 被两名警官逮捕
我的问题是 如果他真的杀了他的父亲...
为什么他会在 三个小时后回到家里？
难道他不怕会被逮到吗？
他是回来拿刀子的，他不想 让刀子继续插在死者胸口上
对，而且死的人是他老爸
我一点都不觉得好笑 他知道会有人指认出...
那是他的刀子 他得抢在警察前面拿走刀子
如果他知道凶刀会被指认出来 案发时他为什么要把它留在现场？
我们可以假设那孩子杀了父亲后 慌张地逃离现场
他冷静下来后 才发现他把刀子留在现场
这得视你对慌张的定义 来做判断
他必须非常地冷静 才会想到要把刀子的指纹擦干净
他什么时候感到慌张 又在什么时候冷静下来的呢？
你投了“有罪”一票 你到底站在哪一边
我不必效忠于任何一边 我只是提出了我的疑问
这真的已经超出了我的理解范围 但是....
如果我是他，我真的杀了人 我会回案发现场取回刀子
他认为没有人看到他离开现场 尸体要到隔天才会被发现
那时是三更半夜的
- 他认为没有人会发现尸体 - 对不起，那就是我的重点
那女人在法庭上说 在凶案发生之后- -
在电车经过后不久...
她放声大叫 并且打电话报警
那个孩子一定 听到了尖叫声
他一定知道 有人看到了他杀人
我想他是打死都不会回家的
或许他太过惊慌没有听到尖叫声 或许她没有叫得很大声
或许他没有想到 她是看到他杀人才会放声大叫
在他住的地方 听见尖叫声是司空见惯的事
- 事情就是那么简单 - 或许是吧
或是他真的杀了他父亲 他没有听到尖叫声...
他慌张地冲出屋子 事后他冷静下来...
冒着被抓的风险 回家去拿他的刀子
或许这就是事实 或许根本不是这么一回事
还有很多疑点能让我们去怀疑 案发时他到底在不在现场
你在胡说什么？ 那个老头子看到他冲出屋外
他是在扭曲事实
十二点十分时 那个老人到底有没有看到被告？
- 他到底有没有看到？ - 他说他看到了
- 他说他看到了 - 听着，证人也是会犯错的
没错，那都是你在胡说八道 他根本没有说谎
- 小声一点 - 或许我们该大声地说出来
这些家伙越来越过份了 他到底听到了尖叫声吗？
你们只会去讨论 那些微乎其微的小细节
却忘了最重要的事
- 我提议再投一次票 - 我在说话吔
有人要求再投一次票 大家请坐下
我从来没看过 有人把时间浪费在这种小事上
只要一下子就好了
最快的方法是先表决 “无罪”的部份
要投“无罪”一票的人 请举手
还是一样，三票无罪 九票有罪
听我说，再这样耗下去 我们得在这里待到下星期二
这对我们有什么好处呢？
对不起，我要投“无罪”一票
他在胡说什么？ 大家全都疯了
那个孩子有罪 你们为什么不愿意相信事实？
这个案子会变成一个大笑话
票数是八比四 有罪占优势
这是怎么一回事 “支持弱势团体周”到了吗？
告诉我你为什么会改变心意 把理由给我说清楚
我不必为我的决定辩护 我心里头出现了合理的怀疑
什么怀疑？证词非常明确 听我说
有人看到你认为无罪的那个孩子 拿刀杀了他的父亲
- 那又是怎么一回事？ - 那并不是凶刀，你还记得吗？
太棒了
我得告诉你们这件事太疯狂了
我们到底要相信什么？ 你们凭空编出许多故事
这家伙要是看过 丹柏西跟佛波的比赛...
或许他会告诉你们....
那个老头又是怎么一回事？ 我们要相信他没有跑到门边...
在案发后十五秒 他没有看到那孩子冲出屋外？
他那么说只是想引人注意，对吧？
- 你到底想说什么？ - 等一下
巴尔的摩队的球迷欢声雷动 球员击出安打现场纸花四射
那个老头说 他跑到了门口
他用跑的或用走的又有什么差别 总之他是到了门口
- 等一下- -  - 我确定他说他是用跑的
他根本就没办法跑步
他说他从房间 跑到了门口
- 他的房间在哪里？ - 就在走廊的尽头
你记得所有的细节 却不记得那一点？
我是不记得了 我想看看那栋公寓的配置图
我们为什么 不叫他们再开一次庭？
只有你想看公寓的配置图
- 我也想看 - 我不想再浪费时间了
如果我们要把时间 浪费在这些胡言乱语上- -
这不是在浪费时间，我想要知道 一个跛脚的老人...
能不能在十五秒内 从他的房间跑到门口
- 是二十秒才对 - 他说十五秒
他要二十秒 你为什么要扭曲事实？
他说十五秒
他怎么会知道 十五秒到底是多久？
他说十五秒 他非常肯定
他是个老头子 他的脑袋有一半的时间不太清楚
他怎么能那么肯定 他看到的事都是对的？
我不知道你想证明什么 这老头的确看到那个孩子了
我们来看看他说的话是不是真的
他说他听到楼上传来脚步声 脚步声一路传到了门口
他听到门打开的声音 还听到有人冲下楼
他跑到大门口 非常肯定整个过程只有十五秒
- 凶手拔腿就跑- -  - 他没有那么说
那老头真的是那么说的
你应该去参加 吹毛求疵大会
你为什么 还要装出自以为聪明的样子？
当陪审员一天只能赚三块钱- -
现在你害我们被困在这里 你到底有什么好处？
这就是案发现场
老人的家就在楼下 隔局完全是一样的
这是走道，客厅，浴室
这是走廊，楼梯 当时老人在他的卧房里
他打开了房门 一路冲到走廊的另一端...
他及时打开大门 看到那孩子冲下楼梯
他一再陈述着这样的证词
离他听到有人倒在地上的声音 只差了十五秒
- 没错 - 现在让我们来看看....
床铺离房门有十二尺 走廊有四十三尺长
他得走上十二尺的距离 打开房门...
走过四十三尺长的走廊 再打开大门，一共只花掉十五秒
- 你觉得他办得到吗？ - 当然可以
他走起路来非常慢 还要法警来扶他
你讲得好像这条路很远
对一个中过风的老人来说 这段路的确很远
- 你在做什么？ - 我打算亲自实验一下
什么？ 他的律师为什么不那么做？
- 或许他没有想到这一点 - 你是什么意思？
- 这太明显了 - 而你就想到了这一点？
他没有提出这一点 因为这对他很不利
你觉得呢？
他没有提出这一点 因为那证明了老人在说谎
陪审团不喜欢这样的事 律师会尽量避免发生这种事
- 他到底是个什么样的人？ - 我一直在问这个问题
请把那张椅子拿过来给我
我们用这些椅子来代表床 我要量出十二尺的距离
- 这里就是房门口 - 你不能那样子重建现场
- 我知道答案是什么 - 我要走到那道墙边再走回来
你为什么要浪费大家的时间 把我们困在这里？
根据你的说法这个部份 只花十五秒，我们要证明这一点
喂，别吹了
好吧，大天才
你站在那里当大门
还记得吗？当时大门上了门链
- 谁的手表有秒针？ - 我的手表有
你准备好后就跺脚暗示我 然后开始帮我计时
- 我们要来玩比手划脚的游戏吗？ - 我们还在等什么？
我得等到秒针归零 才能开始计时
少来了
快一点 他走起路来的速度比你快两倍
你要我走快一点吗？ 没问题
- 开锁，打开门，停 - 好
- 时间是多少？ - 四十一秒整
- 四十一秒？ - 我想这才是真正的事实
案发数小时前 老人听到了争吵声
后来他躺在床上 听到有人倒在地上的声音...
他听到了尖叫声 拼了老命地跑到大门口...
他听到了脚步声 以为是那个孩子
- 我想那是有可能的 - 那都是他的推测
我看过各式各样的骗局 但你的示范真的是太惊人了
你们带着一份热忱 去同情那些小混混跟非正义
你们听到他编出来的故事 完全忘了什么才是真相
你是骗不过我的 我受够了
你们是怎么了？ 你们知道那孩子有罪！
你们要让他逃过法律的制裁
- 你是他的刽子手吗？ - 我是其中一个
- 你想亲自按下开关 - 我的确想亲自帮那孩子行刑
我为你感到遗憾 只有疯子才想亲自按下电椅开关
你一走进这里 就一付想替天行道的模样
你出自一片私心 想看到那孩子被判死刑
你是个虐待狂
放开我，我要杀了他 我要杀了他
你该不会 真的想杀了我吧？
怎么了？我听到吵闹声
没事 我们只是起了一点小争执
我们已经看过了配置图 请你把它拿走
拿去吧，谢谢你
你们在看什么？
- 我想得有人站出来发言 - 对不起
“对不起”？ 你干嘛变得那么有礼貌？
就跟你没有礼貌的理由一样 我从小就是个有礼貌的人
我们会来这里 不是来吵架的
我们肩负着重责大任
我一直觉得 这就是民主社会的优点
我们- -
该怎么说呢？我们被通知
我们收到信 被通知要来这里...
决定一个跟我们 素昧平生的人到底有没有罪
不论做出什么样的判决 我们都拿不到好处，也没有损失
那就是我们的国家 能这么强大的原因
我们不应该把这件事 跟私人的感觉扯上关系
谢谢
如果没有人想发言，我有个主意
现在把事情摊在阳光下 看看我们能不能得到结论
- “得到结论” - 没错
外面的天色非常暗
我猜应该是要下大雨了
天啊，真的好热
对不起，你从来都不流汗吗？
我不流汗的
听着，我在想...
或许我们该再投一次票
太棒了，或许我们接下来 该跳个舞，吃点东西来庆祝一下
- 团长先生？ - 我没有意见
有人反对进行投票吗？
- 来吧 - 什么？对不起
我们应该做公开投票 表明自己的意愿
- 来看看每个人的立场是什么 - 我觉得听起来挺公平的
有人反对吗？
好吧，我会照编号来叫大家，一号
我是一号，我投“有罪”，二号？
无罪
三号？
有罪
四号？
五号？
无罪
六号？
七号？
有罪
八号？
无罪
九号？
十号？
有罪
十一号？
无罪
十二号？
有罪
现在的票数是六比六
没错，我们现在 要打延长赛了，对吧？
六比六
你们之中有些人一定是疯了
像他那样的孩子没救了
我觉得他是什么样的孩子 跟这件事无关
- 事实可以决定一切 - 少拿那一套来唬我
我厌倦了事实 反正到最后你也会扭曲一切
那就是这个先生所强调的重点
你一直扯着嗓门 对我们大吼大叫的
真希望我能年轻个几岁 那家伙害得我....
- 真的好热喔 - 你要喝点水吗？
不用了，谢谢你
快下雨了
你怎么知道呢？ 大天才
你为什么会改变心意？
这个案子看起来 真的有值得质疑的地方
- 你根本就是墙头草 - 我不那么认为
- 很多的细节并没有查清楚 - 祝你好运
少来了，你跟其他人一样 你想的太多反而被弄迷糊了
- 你瞭解我的意思吗？ - 我不认为你有权利- -
大嘴巴
看看这场大雨
你知道吗？这让我想起 之前遇到的一场西北雨....
那是十一月的事吗？ 我不知道，可能是吧
那场雨下的真大 当时球赛进行到一半
我们以六比七落后 那时由我们来进攻
做出了一个漂亮的擒抱 开始切往右边，一路往前冲
队上有个孩子姓史拉特利
他就跟一头蛮牛一样
我巴不得能找到 另一个跟他一模一样的球员
我是安德鲁麦柯克高中 足球位的助理总教练
那所学校在皇后区
总之我们的攻势 非常地顺利
你知道的 对手的防守阵线开始崩溃
突然间天空开始下起大雨 雨势就跟这场雨一样大
那场雨来的很突然
那真是要人命，你知道吗？
我发誓那时我差点要疯了 你真的是一点办法都没有
没错
这个电扇到底是怎么一回事？ 怎么会...
嘿，看
原来是要从电灯的开关 来启动它
局势开始好转了，对吧
没错
天啊，凉快多了
进了
你们去过花园广场吗？
那么做真的是太蠢了
对不起，我....
你知道吗？
对不起
你觉得如何呢？现在是平分 令人跌破眼镜吧
没错
那个叫什么来着的高个儿...
想要引我上钩时 但那无法证明任何事
他为什么要说我想替天行道 还骂我虐待狂？
谁敢不顺他的心 就会被他狠狠地修理一顿
他只是想引我上钩
他做的太好了
我得告诉你，我们无法做出结论 我准备宣布本案将成为悬判
- 我们无法再继续谈下去 - 我赞成你的说法
把那个孩子 交给下一批陪审员来处理
我不认为法官会接受 悬判的判决
- 我们走着瞧吧 - 我不打算那么做
把本案交给下一批陪审员 那孩子是死路一条
我们无法做出结论 没有人能改变那家伙的决定
- 你还是觉得这个案子很合理？ - 没错
对不起，或许你不瞭解 “合理怀疑”的意思
你说我不瞭解是什么意思？
天啊，你对这家伙有什么看法 他们全都是一个样子
他们来到这里 他们椅子都还没有坐热...
就急着告诉我们 该怎么做出判决
这个家伙真的是太傲慢了
好吧，请大家暂时 停止争执
谁想发表有建设性的意见？
如果大家不介意的话 我有一些话想说
对检方来说有一件事非常重要 那个孩子说...
案发时 他人在电影院里...
他不记得那部电影 及片中演员的名字
这位先生提到了重点
没错，那是被告 提出的唯一不在场证明
但他无法说明 所有的细节
你觉得 被自己的父亲打了巴掌后...
你可以记得起 这些小事吗？
我想应该可以 只要这些细节很特别
那孩子什么都记不起来 因为他根本不在电影院里
警方在那孩子家里的厨房 讯问他...
当时他父亲的尸体还躺在地上
在那种情况下 你还想起任何事吗？
- 在那么大的压力下？ - 一点都没错
他在法庭上想起所有细节 说出电影跟演员的名字
对，他的律师花了一番力气 才让他说出来
从案发到接受审判 他有好几个月的时间回想细节
要查出某家电影院 当时在放映那部电影并不难
我相信那个孩子 在案发后...
记不起电影名字的证词 不论他当时是否承受极大的压力
- 我想问你一个问题 - 请说
- 昨天晚上你在哪里？ - 我在家里
- 前天晚上呢？ - 这是什么意思？
没关系，我不在意
我八点半下班 然后就回家了
- 大前天晚上呢？ - 那是星期二晚上
- 那天我去打桥牌了 - 星期一晚上呢？
回想到1954年的新年除夕时 再来叫我
星期一晚上吗？
星期一晚上 我跟我太太去看电影
- 你们看了哪部电影
- 第二部是什么呢？ - 是....
我待会再告诉你
《TheRemarkableMrs》.... 什么来着....
《TheRemarkableMrs.Bainbridge.》
我看过那部电影，它叫做 《TheAmazingMrs.Bainbridge.》
没错
的主角是谁呢？
芭芭拉隆格 我觉得她是个漂亮的黑美人
她应该是姓林德或隆格
- 还有谁呢？ - 我从来没有听过他们的名字
它是一部低成本的二线电影 请了名不见经传....
当时你并没有承受 极大的情绪压力吧
没有
- 我想重点大家都瞭解了 - 好大的重点喔
你爱怎么说随便你 那孩子还是有罪
你瞭解我的意思吗？
- 你还有喉糖吗？ - 已经吃完了
天啊，雨下的还真大 看来你的球赛应该会取消
这只是一场阵雨
而且内野一定会盖上防水布
我能再看看那把刀子吗？
现在票数还是六比六平手 有人有任何建议吗？
- 已经过了六点，去吃晚餐吧 - 等到七点再说，再谈一小时吧
我没有意见
我有一件事想说
这件事一直让我觉得很困扰 既然我们被困在这里....
对于死者的致命伤 跟其成因我一直觉得不太对劲
- 伤口的角度向下 - 你们又来了
- 律师们已经讨论过这一点 - 我知道，但我就是觉得不对劲
那孩子五尺七寸高 他父亲是六尺二寸高
他们的身高相差七寸
要往下刺伤一个比你高半尺的人 不是一件很简单的事
请把刀子递给我
我来示范给你们看 麻烦哪位过来一下
大家仔细看着 我不会再示范第二次
我会往下蹲 让自己比他矮上七寸，好吗？
- 大概是这样，还要再低一点 - 好了，再蹲低一点
别担心....我不会来真的
- 是吗？ - 没有人会受伤的
我就是这样 刺伤比我高的人
你们看看这个角度是往下压的
他就是这样杀了他父亲 你们可以说我错了
- 角度往下压，一定不会错的 - 请等一下
麻烦你把刀子递给我
天啊，我恨透这些事了
- 你看过别人互砍的样子吗？ - 没有
- 你呢？ - 没有
有人看过别人互砍的样子吗？
我看过
当时我曲着身体 他们在对街的院子里械斗
在我住的社区里 拥有摺叠刀不是稀奇的事
我不想去想起这种事 一直都努力地想忘了它
- 你都是怎么使用摺叠刀的？ - 没有人会这样使用摺叠刀
这样子要亮出刀子 会浪费掉太多时间
大家都是这样向下拿着刀子
使用摺叠刀的人 都是这样拿刀子的
- 你确定？ - 我非常确定
- 那样子才能把刀子弹开 - 那孩子对使用刀子非常熟悉
你觉得他有办法 那样杀死他父亲吗？
不可能，除非经过练习 不然他不可能是那样拿刀子的
- 他一定是偷偷地攻击他的 - 你怎么知道？
- 你当时也在现场吗？ - 不，当时现场没有其他人
你凭什么告诉我们 这些凭空杜撰的事？
我不认为你可以 判定那孩子是怎么杀人的...
因为他知道如何使用刀子
你觉得呢？
- 我不知道 - 你是什么意思？
我不知道
你呢？
我不知道其他人是怎么想的 但我已经厌倦了这种情况
这样子下去是不会有结论的 我想我要做出突破
我要改变决定，投“无罪”一票
- 你说什么？ - 你都听到了，我受够了
什么？那不是答案
听着，你只要搞定 你自己就好了，你知道吗？
他说的对，那不是答案
你到底是什么样的人？
你刚刚还投“有罪”一票 赞同其他人的意见...
只因为你急着要去看球赛
现在你改变了心意 因为你厌倦了这些讨论
听我说，兄弟
谁告诉你你有权 这样子玩弄别人的生命？
- 你不在乎吗？ - 等一下
- 你不能那样子跟我说话 - 我当然可以那样子跟你说话
如果你要投“无罪”一票 必须是因为你相信...
被告的确是无罪的 而不是因为你觉得厌烦
如果你觉得他有罪 你得坚持下去
难道你没有种 去做你认为是对的事吗？
- 听我说- -  - 你认为他有罪或无罪
- 我说过了他无罪 - 为什么？
听着，我不必- -
你非说出来不可，为什么？
好吧，我不认为他有罪
- 我要求再投一次票 - 好的，有人要求再投一次票
最快的方法是举手
好吧，认为被告“无罪”的人 请举手
一，二，三，四 五，六，七...
八
九
认为被告“有罪”的人 请举手
一，二，三
票数是九比三 无罪的一方占优势
我搞不清楚你们这些人
你们提出的那些细节 根本一点都不重要
你们跟我都看到了那个孩子
你们相信 他说他的刀子不见了...
案发时他在看电影的说词
这些人在说谎 那是他们天生的劣根性
不必我来提醒你们 他们根本不知道什么是事实
听我说 那些人杀人是不必有理由的
他们喝醉了 他们全都烂醉如泥
突然间有人倒在水沟里 没有人怪他们
那就是他们天生的劣根性 你们懂吗？他们有暴力倾向
你要去哪里？
他们的想法跟我们一样 人命是不值钱的
他们老是打成一团 就算有人死了，他们也不在乎
他们之间还是有好人 我是第一个会那么说的人
我认识一两个还不错的混混 但那是例外
大部份的人都很无情 他们什么事都做得出来
这是怎么一回事？
我试着告诉你们 你们犯了大错，那孩子是骗子
我知道，我太瞭解那些人了
听我说，他们都是大坏蛋 他们之中根本没有好人
这到底是怎么一回事？
我说出我的想法，你们- -
听我说
被告是个小混混 难道你们不瞭解他们那种人吗？
他们是危险人物
这些人很危险
他们真疯狂
听我说
- 听着 - 我在听
请你坐下 把你的嘴巴闭上
有时候....我告诉你....
面对这种事 要排除个人的偏见真的很难
不论去到哪里 偏见总是遮蔽了真相
我真的不知道真相是什么
我想应该没有任何人 知道真相是什么
我们九个人现在觉得 被告是无辜的...
但我们是在赌一个可能性 或许我们错了
我们或许会放走一个杀人犯 我不知道
没有人知道 但我们有合理的怀疑...
那是我们的司法制度中 非常珍贵的一部份
除非十分确定 陪审团无法判决被告有罪
我们九个人不瞭解 你们三个为什么还那么地确定
- 或是你们可以好好解释一下 - 我会的
有说地方你的确很有说服力 但我相信那孩子有罪...
原因有二
一是目赌凶案经过的那位女士 在法庭上做出的证词
那是最重要的证词
二是她描述她看到的凶案经过 她说她看到那个孩子...
双手高举过头 拿刀往他父亲的胸口刺下
- 她看到他杀了人 - 一点都没错
我们来谈谈这位女士
她说案发当晚 她大约在十一点上床睡觉
她的床就在窗户旁边 只要她一往外看...
她可以看到那孩子 在对街的房间
那晚她翻来覆去 大约一个小时
大约在十二点十分 她转身面向窗户...
她往外一看...
透过电车车窗 看到杀人的经过
她说在凶案发生后 四周是一片漆黑...
但她非常清楚地看到 那孩子拿刀刺向他父亲
在我的看法里 这项证词坚不可破
- 就是那么一回事 - 你有什么看法？
你觉得呢？
我不知道
很多证词都有待调查 这是一个很复杂的案子
老实说我不明白 你们为什么会认为他无罪？
要安排这样的证词 并不容易
抛开其他的证据不谈 那位女士真的看到他了
你还要什么样的证据呢？
- 或许- -  - 我们来投票吧
好吧，有人要求再度投票 有人反对吗？
好吧，我改变了心意 他有罪
其他人呢？现在票数是八比四
为什么你那么得意呢？ 那只是一票
我说过此案会形成悬判 这样子告诉法官吧
你们觉得如何呢？ 我想听听大家的意见
这都是你惹出来的 你觉得如何呢？
- 我们再来讨论一次 - 我们已经讨论过了
那孩子像球一样 被我们踢来踢去
我们不该再折磨他了 你只是想为自己争一口气
好吧
或许我们该应该 订出一个最后期限
时间一到我们就得做出结论
现在是六点十五分 之前有人提过七点要吃晚餐
我们就讨论到七点 不论这个案子会不会形成悬判
- 你不舒服吗？ - 我很好，谢谢你
我觉得讨论到七点 是个合理的- -
我会那么说是因为 你一直在按摩你的鼻子- -
对不起，你的动作 让我想起了一件事
- 我正在说服大家订出规则来 - 我觉得这件事非常重要
谢谢你
我相信 你会原谅我这么说...
我一直在想 你为什么要那样按摩你的鼻子
少来了
我是在跟 坐在你隔壁的先生说话
你为什么要那样按摩你的鼻子？
我会这么做 是因为我觉得鼻子很痛
对不起 那是因为你戴眼镜的关系吗？
没错 我们可以谈正事了吗？
你的眼镜在鼻梁侧面 压出那些很深的印子
我之前没有注意到 那应该会很痛
你说的对
我不瞭解那种感觉 我的视力很好，没有戴过眼镜
请你别谈这些 眼科医生才会关心的事，好吗？
出庭作证 说她看到凶案经过的那位女士...
鼻梁侧面 也有相同的印子
- 天啊，他说的对 - 请安静
再给我一点时间 让我把话说完
我不知道其他人是否注意到
那时我并不在意 但我的脑海中一直浮现她的脸庞
她脸上也有这样的印子 她在法庭上也一直在按摩鼻子
他说的对，她的确常常那么做
这位女士大约是四十五岁
她很努力让自己 看起来只有三十五岁的样子
她化了浓妆，染了头发...
穿上年轻女孩 才会穿的新衣服
她没有戴眼镜，女人常那么做 你们应该能瞭解她们的心态
你是什么意思？ 你怎么知道她有戴眼镜？
- 就因为她会按摩鼻子吗？ - 她脸上也有那种印子
- 你觉得那代表什么意思？ - 我厌倦了你总是大吼大叫- -
好了，别激动
听着，他说的对，我也看到了 我是最靠近她的人
她鼻子上也有那些印子 这是叫什么来着的？
你想要证明什么？ 她染了头发，鼻子上有印子
那代表什么意思？
这些印子可能是除了眼镜以外 的其他东西造成的吗？
不可能
我没看到她鼻子上有印子
我看到了，奇怪的是 我之前没有想到这一点
律师呢？ 他为什么没有提出质疑？
这个房间里有十二个人 有十一个人也没有想到这一点
检察官呢？
你觉得是他要她 在出庭时拿下眼镜吗？
有些女人不喜欢戴眼镜 因为戴上眼镜她们会变得很丑
好吧，她的鼻子上有印子
我承认这一点 那是眼镜造成的，对吧？
她不想戴上眼镜 那样子大家会觉得她很漂亮
但她看到那孩子杀死他父亲时 她是一个人待在房里
就是那样
你会戴着眼镜睡觉吗？
我不会那么做 没有人会戴着眼镜睡觉
所以我们可能合理地推论 她躺在床上时并没有戴眼镜
- 你怎么知道？ - 那是我的推论
我推论她往窗外看去时 并没有戴眼镜
她作证说 案发时她刚好往窗外看去
她根本没有时间 把眼镜戴上
- 等一下- -  - 还有另一个推论
她真的认为她看到了那个孩子 但我觉得她只看到模糊的影子
你怎么知道她看到了什么？ 他怎么会知道那么多事？
你怎么知道她戴的是哪一种眼镜？ 或许她得的是远视？
- 你怎么会知道？ - 那个女人的视力现在成了争议
她得在昏暗的夜色中不戴眼镜 辨识出六十尺外的人
只靠这样的证据 你不能让一个人坐上电椅
少来这一套
- 你觉得她看错了吗？ - 不
- 那是不可能的吗？ - 那是不可能的
这可能吗？
他是无罪的
你觉得他有罪吗？
我觉得他有罪
你呢？
他无罪
我被说服了，他无罪
- 你是怎么了？ - 我现在有了合理的怀疑
现在是十一比一
其他的证据又是怎么一回事？ 那把凶刀跟其他的证据呢？
你说过我们可以抛开 其他的证据
我们现在该怎么办？
你只剩下一个人
我不在乎自己是不是孤军奋战 这是我的权利
这是你的权利
你们打算怎么办？ 我认为他有罪
- 我们要听听你的说法 - 我该说的都说了
我们不相信你的说法 我们想再听一次
我们有的是时间
所有的证据
在法庭上做出的所有证词 都证明他有罪
难道你们认为我是白痴吗？
你们为什么不相信...
住在楼下的老人听到了声音？
你们推翻了凶刀的理论 就因为我们找到了类似的刀子？
那个老人看到他 从楼上冲了下来
他到底花了几秒跑到门口 那有什么差别？
所有的证据
刀子从他口袋的破洞 掉了出去
你不能证明 他没有夺门而出
你可以量时间，蹒跚地走来走去 但你无法证明那一点
关于电车 跟电影院又是怎么一回事呢？
我非常确定 那都是他编出来的谎言
我跟你赌五千块 我可以记得我看过的电影
我告诉你们 所有的事实都遭到了扭曲
关于眼镜的理论
你怎么知道当时她没有戴眼镜？ 这位女士在法庭上作证
还有那孩子的喊叫声呢？
我告诉你们 我知道什么才是事实
好了
够了，这就是事实
你们觉得呢？
快说啊
你们是一群狠心的混蛋
你们无法威胁我 我要坚持我的想法
该死的孩子，你毁了自己的一生
不....
他无罪
我们准备好了
嘿
- 你叫什么名字？ - 我是戴维斯
我叫迈卡迪
- 再见了 - 再见
Thank you very much, sir.
You did a wonderful job. Wonderful.
Shh. Shh.
We did it, Pete. We did it.
- For a moment, we had our doubts.
- Shh.
To continue, you've listened
to a long and complex case...
murder in the first degree.
A premeditated murder is the most serious
charge tried in our criminal courts.
You've listened to the testimony.
You've had the law read to you
and interpreted as it applies in this case.
It's now your duty to sit down and try
and separate the facts from the fancy.
One man is dead.
Another man's life is at stake.
If there's a reasonable doubt in your minds
as to the guilt of the accused...
a reasonable doubt...
then you must bring me
a verdict of not guilty.
Now if, however,
there's no reasonable doubt...
then you must in good conscience
find the accused guilty.
However you decide,
your verdict must be unanimous.
In the event
that you find the accused guilty...
the bench will not entertain
a recommendation for mercy.
The death sentence
is mandatory in this case.
You're faced with a grave responsibility.
Thank you, gentlemen.
The alternate jurors are excused.
The jury will now retire.
Try this one. See if I can get it...
It's a muggy day.
Hey. Oh, oh.
- Piece of gum?
- No, thanks.
This thing is...
- Huh?
- ...move it.
- Come on, I'll give you a hand.
- Give me a hand with that.
That's it.
- You know something?
- Yeah?
I called the weather bureau this morning.
This is gonna be
the hottest day of the year.
Could be.
Boy, you'd think they'd at least
air-condition these places.
- What is your name, sir?
- Oh, it's, uh - That one, yeah.
Thank you very much.
Okay, gentlemen, everybody's here.
Now, if there's anything you want,
I'll be right outside the door.
- Just knock.
- Okay, thanks. We will.
Good morning.
I never knew they locked the door.
Sure they lock the door.
What'd you think?
I don't know.
It just never occurred to me.
What's that for?
Oh, I thought we might want
to vote by ballot.
Great idea. Maybe we can
get him elected senator.
Just in case, you know.
- Ηow'd you like it?
- Oh, I don't know.
It was pretty interesting.
Yeah? I almost fell asleep.
I mean, I've never been
on a jury before.
No? I've sat on many juries.
What gets me is the way
those lawyers talk and talk and talk...
even when it's an open-and-shut case
like this one.
Did you ever hear
so much talk about nothin'?
Well, I guess they're entitled.
Yeah. They're entitled.
It's the system, but...
If you ask me, I'd slap those tough kids
down before they start any trouble.
It would save us a lot of time and money.
- Hey, let's get started, huh?
- That's a good idea.
- Yeah, let's get goin', huh?
- We probably all got things to do here.
I figured we'd start out with a five-minute break.
There's one gentleman in the bathroom.
- Mr. Foreman.
- Huh?
- Are, uh - Are we gonna sit in order?
- Gee, I don't know.
I, uh - Well, I guess so.
Uh, you're in my seat.
- Oh. Excuse me.
- That's all right.
Hey, that's not a bad view, huh?
What did you think of the case?
I mean, it had a lot of interest for me.
No real... dead spots.
You know what I mean?
I tell you, we were lucky
to get a murder case.
I figured us for an assault or burglary.
Boy, they can be the dullest.
Hey.
That the Woolworth Building?
That's right.
Isn't that funny?
You know, I've lived here all my life.
I've never been inside that.
If you had to sort out all that junk...
Like that thing with the movies.
- Yeah. You can say that again.
- And what about that business with the knife?
I mean, asking grown-up people
to believe that kind of jazz, huh?
Well, I expected that.
You know what we're dealing with.
Yeah, I guess so.
Well, your horn works.
Now try your lights.
- What do you got, a cold?
- And how.
These hot-weather colds can kill you.
I can hardly touch my nose.
You know what I mean?
I sure do. I just got over one.
Aw, come on. Mr.
Foreman, let's go here, huh?
Well, that guy's still in the bathroom.
Hey, what's new? I didn't get a chance
to see a paper this morning.
Hmm?
I was only wondering
how the market closed.
You got a seat on the Exchange?
I'm a broker.
I run a messenger service -
the Beck and Call Company.
The name is my wife's idea.
Got 37 men working.
Started with nothing.
Okay, men, let's take our seats, huh?
Yeah, we can all get outta here
pretty quick, huh?
I don't know about the rest of you, but I happen
to have tickets to that ball game tonight.
Yanks and Cleveland.
Yeah, we got this kid,
Modjelewski, in there.
Ooh, he's a real bull, this kid.
You know - Phoom!
A real jug handle. You know?
Phoom!
You're a real baseball fan, aren't you?
Huh? Yeah.
Where do we sit here?
Well, I thought we'd sit in order,
you know, by jury numbers.
One, two, three, four, five -
so on, around the table.
If that's okay with you gentlemen.
- Sure.
- What's the difference?
- I think it's reasonable to sit in order.
- Let it be.
- Number 12. Do I sit down here?
- Yeah. That's 12. We go around...
- We start with you. One, right?
- One, yeah. Two, three, four, five, six.
What was your impression
of the prosecuting attorney?
Okay. Two. You're two.
I beg pardon?
I thought he was really sharp, the way
he handled all those points one by one.
Logical sequence.
I was very impressed.
I think he - he did an expert job.
A lot of drive too, you know?
Real drive.
- Okay, fellas, can we hold it down a minute?
- Sure.
Uh, fellas.
Say, we'd like to get started.
Gentleman at the window.
- We'd like to get started.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
Pretty tough to figure, isn't it?
Kid kills his father - bing, just like that.
Aw, listen, you analyze the figures,
you'll see it happens all the time.
They let those kids
run wild up there.
Well, maybe it serves 'em right.
You know what I mean?
Is - Is everyone here?
The old man is inside.
Oh. Would you, uh,
knock on the door for him?
You a Yankee fan?
No. Baltimore.
- Baltimore?
- Yeah.
That's like being hit in the head
with a crowbar once a day.
Who have they got?
No, I mean, who have they got
besides good groundskeepers?
Say, uh, we'd like to get started.
Oh, forgive me, gentlemen.
I - I didn't mean to keep you waiting.
Baltimore?
Okay, gentlemen,
if I can have your attention.
You fellas can handle this thing
any way that you want to.
I'm, um - You know,
I'm not gonna make any rules.
Uh, we can, well, discuss it first
and, uh, then vote on it.
That's, of course, uh -
That's, uh, one way.
And, uh, well, we can
vote on it right now, and...
I think it's customary
to take a preliminary vote.
Yeah, let's - Let's vote. Who knows?
Maybe we all can get outta here, huh?
Uh-huh.
Okay, then I think that, uh...
Of course you know that we have
a first-degree murder charge here...
and if we vote the accused guilty...
uh, we've got to send him
to the chair.
- Um, that's mandatory.
- I think we know that.
- Let's see who's where.
- We might as well.
- Okay. Uh, anyone doesn't want to vote?
- All right with me.
Okay. Then, uh, just remember that this
has to be 12 to nothing either way.
Um, that's the law.
Okay, are we ready?
Now, all those voting guilty,
please raise your hands.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
eight, nine, 10, 11.
Okay. That's 11 guilty.
Those voting not guilty.
One. Right.
That's 11 guilty. One not guilty.
Well, now we know where we are.
Boy, oh, boy. There's always one.
So, what do we do now?
Well, I guess we talk.
Boy, oh, boy.
You really think he's innocent?
I don't know.
I mean, you sat in court with the rest of us.
You heard what we did.
The kid's a dangerous killer.
You could see it.
He's 18 years old.
Well, that's old enough. Ηe...
He stabbed his own father
four inches into the chest.
They proved it
a dozen different ways in court.
Would you like me to list them for you?
No.
Then what do you want?
- I just want to talk.
- What's there to talk about?
Eleven men in here think he's guilty.
No one had to think about it twice
except you.
I want to ask you something.
Do you believe his story?
I don't know whether I believe it or not.
Maybe I don't.
So how come you vote not guilty?
Well, there were 11 votes for guilty.
It's not easy to raise my hand
and send a boy off to die...
without talking about it first.
- Well, now, who says it's easy?
- No one.
What, just because I voted fast?
I honestly think the guy's guilty.
You couldn't change my mind
if you talked for a hundred years.
I'm not trying to change your mind.
It's just that...
We're talking about somebody's life here.
We can't decide it in five minutes.
Supposing we're wrong.
"Supposing we're wrong."
Supposing this whole building
should fall down on my head.
- You can suppose anything.
- That's right.
Look, what's the difference
how long it takes?
Suppose we do it in five minutes.
So what?
Let's take an hour.
The ball game doesn't start till 8:00.
Hmm?
Who's got something to say?
I'm willing to sit for an hour.
Great. I heard
a pretty good story last night.
That's not why we're sitting here.
All right, then you tell me.
What are we sitting here for?
I don't know. Maybe no reason.
Look, this kid's been kicked around
all of his life...
you know, born in a slum,
mother dead since he was nine.
He lived for a year and a half
in an orphanage when his...
his father was serving a jail term
for forgery.
It's not a very happy beginning.
He's a - a wild, angry kid.
That's all he's ever been.
And you know why?
'Cause he's been hit on the head
by somebody once a day every day.
He's had a -
He's had a pretty miserable 18 years.
I - I just think we owe him a few words.
That's all.
I don't mind telling you this, mister.
We don't owe him a thing.
He got a fair trial, didn't he?
What do you think that trial cost?
- He's lucky he got it. You know what I mean?
- You know it.
Now, look, we're all grown-ups in here.
We heard the facts, didn't we?
You're not gonna tell me that we're supposed
to believe this kid, knowing what he is.
Listen, I've lived among them
all my life.
You can't believe a word they say.
You know that.
I mean, they're born liars.
- Only an ignorant man can believe that.
- Now listen...
Do you think you were born
with a monopoly on the truth?
I think certain things should be
pointed out to this man.
- Come on. This isn't Sunday.
- We don't need a sermon.
- Come on.
- We have a job to do. Now let's do it.
Rice Pops.
It's a product I work on at the agency.
"The breakfast with the built-in bounce."
- I wrote that line.
- Very catchy.
- Yeah.
- Say, do you mind?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I have this habit of doodling.
Keeps me thinking clearly.
Yeah, we have all this work to do.
- There's no point staying here forever.
- Sorry.
Okay. Um...
perhaps if the gentleman down there
who's disagreeing with us...
Well, perhaps you could tell us why.
You know, let us know what you're thinking.
And we might be able to show you
where you're mixed up.
Well, look, maybe -
Maybe this is an idea.
Now, I haven't given it much thought,
but it seems to me...
that it's up to the group of us to convince
this gentleman that he's wrong and we're right.
Now, maybe if we each took
a couple of minutes just to...
Well, it was just a quick idea.
No, no, no. That's a good one.
Uh, suppose we go
once around the table.
- I guess you're first.
- Oh.
Well, uh...
Well, it-it's hard to put into words.
I just think he's guilty.
I thought it was obvious
from the word "go."
I mean, nobody proved otherwise.
Nobody has to prove otherwise.
The burden of proof's on the prosecution.
The defendant doesn't even
have to open his mouth.
- That's in the Constitution.
- Oh, well, sure, I know that.
Uh, what I meant was, is...
Well, I just think he's guilty.
I-I mean, somebody saw him do it.
Okay. Uh, here's what I think,
and I have no personal feelings about this.
I just want to talk about facts.
Number one.
The old man lived downstairs under the room
where the killing took place.
At 10 minutes after 12:00
on the night of the killing...
he heard loud noises,
said it sounded like a fight.
And he heard the kid yell out,
"I'm gonna kill ya."
A second later,
he heard a body hit the floor.
Ran to the door, opened it up...
saw the kid running down the stairs
and out of the house.
Called the police.
They came in, found the old man
with a knife in his chest.
The coroner fixed the time of death
around midnight.
Now these are facts.
You can't refute facts.
The kid is guilty.
I'm just as sentimental as the next fella.
I know he's only 18, but he's still
gotta pay for what he did.
I'm with you.
Okay. Are you finished?
- Yeah.
- Right. Next.
It is obvious, to me anyway,
that the boy's entire story was flimsy.
He claimed he was at the movies
during the time of the killing...
and yet, one hour later, he couldn't
remember the names of the films he saw...
- or who played in them.
- That's right.
And no one saw him going in
or out of the theater.
Listen, what about the woman
across the street?
If her testimony don't prove it,
nothing does.
That's right. She was the one
who actually saw the killing.
- Now, fellas, please.
- Let's go in order here, huh?
Just a minute. Here's a woman...
Here's a woman who was lying in bed.
She can't sleep.
She's dying with the heat.
You know what I mean?
Anyway, she looks out the window...
and right across the street she sees
the kid stick the knife into his father.
The time is 12:10 on the nose.
Everything fits.
Look, she's known the kid all his life.
His window is right opposite hers
across the el tracks...
and she swore she saw him do it.
- Through the windows of the passing el train.
- Right.
This el train had no passengers on it.
It was just being moved downtown.
The lights were out, remember?
And they proved in court that, at night...
you can look through the windows
of an el train when the lights are out...
and see what's happening
on the other side.
- They proved it.
- I'd like to ask you something.
You don't believe the boy's story.
How come you believe the woman's?
She's one of them too, isn't she?
You're a pretty smart fella, aren't you?
- Okay, gentlemen.
- Now, now.
- Now, gentlemen.
- Come on. Sit down. Sit down.
Oh, what's he so wise about?
I'm telling you.
- Okay, now come on.
- Now we're not gonna get anywhere fighting.
Whose turn is it next?
Oh, uh, his. Number five.
Okay, may I - Can I pass? It...
Well, uh, that's your privilege.
Uh, how about the next gentleman?
Oh. Well, uh, I don't know.
I started to be convinced, you know,
very early in the case.
You see, I was looking for a motive.
That's very important.
Because if you don't have a motive,
where's your case, right?
Anyway, that, uh, testimony
from those people...
in the apartment across the hall
from the kid's apartment...
that was very powerful.
Didn't they say something about a -
a fight and an argument...
between the old man and his son
around about, uh, 7:00 that night?
- I mean, I could be wrong, but I -
- It was 8:00.
It was 8:00. That's right.
They heard an argument.
They couldn't hear what it was about.
Then they heard
the father hit the boy twice.
Finally they saw the boy
run angrily out of the house.
What does that prove?
Well, it don't exactly prove anything.
It's just part of the picture.
Well, you said it provided a motive.
The prosecuting attorney said the same thing.
I don't think
that was a very strong motive.
This boy's been hit so many times in his
life that violence is practically a...
It's a normal state of affairs with him.
I just - I can't see two slaps in the face
provoking him into committing murder.
It may have been two too many.
Everyone has a breaking point.
Anything else?
- No.
- Okay.
Uh, how about you?
I don't know. It's all been said.
You can talk here forever.
It's still the same thing.
This kid is five for 0.
Well, look at his record.
When he was 10,
he was in children's court.
He threw a rock at a teacher.
When he was 15, he was in reform school.
He stole a car.
He's been arrested for mugging.
He was picked up twice for knife fighting.
Oh, yeah, they say
he's real handy with a knife.
Oh, this is a very fine boy.
Ever since he was five years old,
his father beat him up regularly.
- He used his fists.
- Well, so would I.
A kid like that?
It's these kids, the way they are nowadays.
When I was a kid,
I used to call my father "sir."
That's right. "Sir."
Do you ever hear a kid
call his father that any more?
Fathers don't seem to think
it's important any more.
- You got any kids?
- Three.
I got one.
Twenty-two years old.
When he was nine years old,
he ran away from a fight.
I saw it. I was so embarrassed
I almost threw up.
I said, "I'm gonna make a man out of you
if I have to break you in two trying."
Well, I made a man out of him.
When he was 16, we had a fight.
Hit me in the jaw.
He was a big kid.
Haven't seen him for two years.
Kids.
Work your heart out.
Well, let's get going.
I think we're missing the point here.
This boy, let's say he's the product
of a broken home and a filthy neighborhood.
We can't help that. We're here to decide
whether he's innocent or guilty...
not to go into the reasons
why he grew up the way he did.
He was born in a slum.
Slums are breeding grounds for criminals.
I know it, and so do you.
It's no secret children from slum backgrounds
are potential menaces to society.
- Now I think -
- Brother, you can say that again.
The kids who crawl out of these places
are real trash.
- I don't want any part of them. I'm telling you.
- Listen, mister. Listen.
- I, uh - I've lived in a slum all my life.
- Wait a minute.
Please, I - I played in backyards
that were filled with garbage.
I mean, maybe you can still
smell it on me.
Now, listen, sonny.
- Come on now.
- There's nothing personal about this.
- No, there was something personal.
- Aw, come on, fella. He didn't mean you.
Let's not be so sensitive.
This sensitivity I can understand.
Okay, look, let's stop the arguing.
We're only wasting time, and...
Look, your turn down there.
Let's go.
Oh, I didn't expect a turn. I thought
you were all gonna try to convince me.
- Wasn't that the idea?
- Check. That was the idea.
- Oh, I forgot about that. He's right.
- What difference does it make?
He's the one who's keeping us in here.
Let's hear what he's got to say.
Oh, now wait a minute.
We decided to do this a certain way.
I think we ought to stick to that way.
Oh, stop being a kid, will you?
- What do you mean "a kid"?
- What do you think I mean?
K-I-D. Kid.
What? Listen, just because I'm trying
to keep this thing organized?
Here, you take it.
You take on the responsibility.
I'll just - I'll keep my mouth shut.
That's all.
What are you getting so hot about?
Calm down, will you?
Don't tell me to calm down.
Here. You wanna take the chair,
just take the chair. That's all.
- Did you ever see such a thing?
- See if you can keep it running.
- Listen, you think it's funny or something?
- Hey, forget it, fella.
The whole thing's unimportant.
Come on.
- Unimportant? Oh, here, you try it.
- No, nobody wants to change.
You're doing a beautiful job.
Sit down.
Yeah, you're doing great.
Just great, fella.
You stay in there and pitch. You know?
All right. Let's hear from somebody.
Well, if you want me to tell you how I
feel about it, it's all right with me.
Boy, I don't care what you do.
All right, I don't have anything brilliant.
I only know as much as you do.
According to the testimony,
the boy looks guilty. Maybe he is.
I sat there in court for six days
listening while the evidence built up.
Everybody sounded so positive, you know?
I-I began to get a peculiar feeling
about this trial.
I mean, nothing is that positive.
There are a lot of questions
I'd have liked to ask.
I don't know. Maybe they wouldn't
have meant anything, but...
I began to get the feeling
that the defense counsel...
wasn't conducting a thorough-enough
cross-examination.
I mean, he - he let too many things go by,
little things that...
What little things? Listen,
when these fellas don't ask questions...
it's because they know the answers already
and they figure they'll be hurt.
Maybe it's also possible for a lawyer
to be just plain stupid, isn't it?
I mean it's possible.
You sound like you met
my brother-in-law once.
I - I kept putting myself
in the kid's place.
I'd have asked for another lawyer, I think.
I mean, if I was on trial for my life...
I'd want my lawyer to tear the prosecution
witnesses to shreds, or at least try to.
Look, there was one alleged eyewitness
to this killing.
Someone else claims he heard the killing,
saw the boy run out afterwards.
And there was a lot
of circumstantial evidence.
But actually, those two witnesses
were the entire case for the prosecution.
Supposing they're wrong.
What do you mean
supposing they're wrong?
What's the point
of having witnesses at all?
- Could they be wrong?
- What are you trying to say?
Those people sat on the stand under oath.
They're only people.
People make mistakes.
Could they be wrong?
- Well, no, I don't think so.
- Do you know so?
Oh, come on.
Nobody can know a thing like that.
This isn't an exact science.
That's right. It isn't.
Okay, let - Let's get to the point.
What about the switch knife
they found in the old man's chest?
Uh, wait-wait a minute.
There's some people who haven't talked yet.
- Shouldn't we go in order?
- They'll get a chance to talk.
Be quiet a second, will you?
What about it, this...
the knife this fine upright boy
admitted buying the night of the killing?
Let's talk about it.
All right, let's talk about it.
Let's get it in here and look at it.
I'd like to see it again.
Mr. Foreman?
- We all saw what it looks like.
- Why do we have to see it again?
The gentleman has a right
to see exhibits in evidence.
Say, could you bring us the knife?
- Knife?
- Yeah. Thank you.
The knife and the way it was bought
is pretty strong evidence, don't you think?
- I do.
- Good.
Now, suppose we take these facts
one at a time.
One. The boy admitted going out of the house
at 8:00 on the night of the murder...
after being slapped several times
by his father.
No, no. No, he didn't say "slapped."
He said "punched."
There's a difference
between a slap and a punch.
After being hit several times
by his father.
Two. He went directly
to a neighborhood junk shop...
- where he bought one of those -
- Switch knives.
Switchblade knives.
This wasn't what you'd call
an ordinary knife.
It had a very unusual carved handle
and blade.
The storekeeper who sold it to him...
said it was the only one of its kind
he had ever had in stock.
Three. He met some friends of his
in front of a tavern about 8:45.
Am I right so far?
- Yes, you are.
- You bet he is.
He talked with his friends for about
an hour, leaving them at 9:45.
During this time,
they saw the switch knife.
Four.
They identified the death weapon
in court...
as that very same knife.
Five. Ηe arrived home at about 10:00.
Now this is where the stories
offered by the State and the boy...
begin to diverge slightly.
He claims that he went to a movie
at about 11:30...
returning home at 3:10 to find his
father dead and himself arrested.
He also claims that
the two detectives who arrested him...
threw him down a half a flight of stairs.
Now, what happened to the switch knife?
He claims that it fell through a hole
in his pocket on the way to the movies...
sometime between 11:30 and 3:10
and that he never saw it again.
Now there's a tale, gentlemen.
I think it's quite clear that the boy
never went to the movies that night.
No one in the house
saw him go out at 11:30.
No one at the theater identified him.
He couldn't even remember
the names of the pictures he saw.
- What actually happened is this.
- Thank you.
The boy stayed home,
had another fight with his father...
stabbed him to death and left the
house at 10 minutes after 12:00.
He even remembered to wipe the knife
clean of fingerprints.
Now are you trying to tell me
that this knife...
really fell through a hole
in the boy's pocket...
someone picked it up off the street,
went to the boy's house...
and stabbed his father with it
just to test its sharpness?
No. I'm just saying it's possible
the boy lost his knife...
and that somebody else stabbed his father
with a similar knife.
It's just possible.
Take a look at this knife.
It's a very unusual knife.
I've never seen one like it.
Neither had the storekeeper
who sold it to the boy.
Aren't you asking us to accept
a pretty incredible coincidence?
I'm just saying a coincidence is possible.
And I say it's not possible.
Where did that come from?
- Where'd you get that?
- It's the same knife.
What do you think you're doing?
Where did you get it?
I went out walking
for a couple of hours last night.
I walked through the boy's neighborhood.
I bought that at a little pawnshop
just two blocks from the boy's house.
It cost six dollars.
It's against the law
to buy or sell switchblade knives.
That's right. I broke the law.
Listen, you pulled a real bright trick.
Now, supposing you tell me what it proves.
Maybe there are 10 knives like that.
So what?
- Maybe there are.
- Well, what does it mean?
You found another knife like it.
What's that, the discovery of the age or something?
You mean you're asking us to believe
that somebody else did the stabbing...
with exactly the same kind of knife?
The odds are a million-to-one.
- It's possible.
- But not very probable.
Okay, fellas, let's take our seats.
There's no point in standing around
all over the place.
You know, it's interesting that he'd find a
knife exactly like the one the boy bought.
What's interesting about it?
"Interesting."
Well, I don't know.
I just thought it was interesting.
There are still 11 of us here
who think he's guilty.
- Right.
- What do you think you're gonna accomplish?
You're not gonna change anybody's mind.
So if you wanna be stubborn
and hang this jury, go ahead.
The kid will be tried again
and found guilty sure as he's born.
That's probably right.
So what are you gonna do?
You know, we could be here all night.
It's only one night. A boy may die.
Well, why don't we just
set up house here, huh?
Someone send for Potsy the policeman
and get a pinochle deck...
and, uh, we'll just
sweat the whole thing out right here.
- I don't think he ought to joke about it.
- What do you want me to do about it?
Oh, listen! I don't see what all this stuff
about the knife's got to do with anything.
Somebody saw the kid stab his father.
What more do we need?
You guys can talk the ears right off my head.
You know what I mean?
I got three garages of mine goin' to pot
while you're talking.
So let's get done and get outta here.
The knife was very important to the
district attorney. He spent a whole day...
He's a 15th assistant or something.
What does he know about it?
Hey, let's hold it down.
These side arguments
are only slowing us up.
Well, what about it?
You're the only one.
I have a proposition
to make to all of you.
I'm gonna call for another vote.
I want you 11 men to vote
by secret written ballot.
I'll abstain.
If there are 11 votes for guilty,
I won't stand alone.
We'll take in a guilty verdict
to the judge right now.
But if anyone votes not guilty,
we stay here and talk it out.
Well, that's it.
If you want to try it, I'm ready.
All right. Let's do it the hard way.
Okay, that sounds fair.
Everyone agreed?
- Anyone doesn't agree?
- Fine, fine. Let's go.
Here, pass these along.
Is that the right time?
"Guilty."
"Not guilty."
Boy, how do you like that?
Oh, and another chap flaps his wings.
All right, who was it?
Come on. I want to know.
Excuse me. This was a secret ballot.
We all agreed on that, no?
If the gentleman wanted
to remain secret...
Secret? What do you mean secret?
There are no secrets in a jury room.
I know who it was.
Brother, you really are something.
You sit here, vote guilty
like the rest of us...
and then some golden-voiced preacher
starts tearin' your poor heart out...
about some underprivileged kid
just couldn't help becomin' a murderer...
and you change your vote.
If that isn't the most sick...
Why don't you drop a quarter
in his collection box?
Oh, now just wait a minute.
Listen, you can't talk to me like that.
- No. Who do you think you are?
- Calm down. Calm down.
No. Who does he think he is?
Did you hear him?
- It doesn't matter. He's very excitable. Sit down.
- Excitable? You bet I'm excitable!
We're trying to put a guilty man
in the chair where he belongs!
Someone starts telling us fairy tales,
and we're listenin'!
Hey, uh, come on, huh?
What made you change your vote?
He didn't change his vote.
I did.
- Oh, fine.
- I knew it.
Would you like me to tell you why?
No, I wouldn't like you to tell me why.
I'd like to make it clear anyway,
if you don't mind.
Do we have to listen to this?
The man wants to talk.
Thank you.
This gentleman has been
standing alone against us.
Now, he doesn't say
the boy is not guilty.
He just isn't sure.
Well, it's not easy to stand alone
against the ridicule of others.
So he gambled for support,
and I gave it to him.
I respect his motives.
The boy on trial is probably guilty,
but, uh, I want to hear more.
Right now, the vote is 10 to two.
I'm talking here!
You have no right to leave this room!
He can't hear you. He never will.
Let's sit down.
Shall we continue?
Well, I - I think we ought
to take a break.
You know, one man's inside,
and I think we ought to wait for him.
Okay.
Looks like we're really
hung up here, huh?
And that thing with the old man,
that was pretty unexpected.
I wish I could figure out some way
we could break it up.
You know, in advertising -
I told you I worked in an agency.
Mm-hmm.
Well, there's some pretty strange people
working there.
Well, they're not strange really, I guess.
It's just that they have peculiar ways
of expressing themselves.
You know what I mean.
Of course, I suppose it's the same
in your business too, huh?
What do you do?
- I'm a watchmaker.
- Oh, really?
Well, I imagine the finest watchmakers
in the world come from Europe, huh?
Anyway, as I was telling you, in an
agency, when we reach a point like this...
I'm telling him about, in an ad agency, when
a point like this is reached in a meeting...
there's always some character
ready with an idea, see.
And it kills me.
It's the weirdest thing in the world...
the way they sometimes precede their idea
with a little phrase, see, like...
Some account exec will get up,
and he'll say, uh...
"Okay, here's an idea.
Let's, uh, run it up the flagpole
and see if anyone salutes it."
I mean, it's idiotic, but it's funny, huh?
I, uh
- I got a little excited back there. I...
didn't mean to get nasty.
I'm glad you're not one of those
lets these emotional appeals influence him.
Uh...
I don't know what's the matter with that fan.
Can't seem to get it to start.
♪ Be, be, be ♪
♪ Ba, ba, ba, ba, bum ♪♪
Eh!
Hey, you a salesman?
I'm an architect.
Hmm.
You know what the soft sell is?
Boy, you got it. Believe me.
I got a different technique.
Laughs, drinks, jokes.
Tricks. You know?
Yeah.
"Hit 'em where they live."
That's my motto.
I made 27 grand last year
sellin' marmalade.
That's not bad. I mean,
you know, considering marmalade.
Hey, what are you
gettin' outta this - kicks?
Or did somebody bump you on the head
one time and you haven't gotten over it?
Maybe.
You know, you do-gooders are all alike.
You're always blowing your stacks
over some guy that fanned.
But what are you wasting our time for?
Why don't you donate five dollars to the
cause, and maybe it'll make you feel better.
This kid is guilty, pal.
It's as plain as the nose on your face.
So why don't we stop
wasting our time here?
We're gonna all get sore throats
if we keep it up, you know?
What difference does it make
if you get it here or at the ball game?
Oh, no difference, pal.
No difference at all.
Nice bunch of guys, huh?
Oh, they're about the same
as anyone else.
Phew! Boy, what a murderous day.
You think we'll be much longer?
I don't know.
Aw, he's guilty for sure.
Not a doubt in the whole world.
We should -
Should've been done already.
Oh, I don't mind, you know.
Hmm. Beats workin'.
Uh...
You think he's not guilty, huh?
I don't know. It's possible.
Well, I don't know you, but I'm bettin'
you never been wronger in your life.
You're wasting your time.
You ought to wrap it up.
Supposing you were the one
who was on trial.
Well, I'm not used to supposing.
I'm just a workingman.
My boss does the supposing. But...
Well, I'll try one.
Supposing you talk us all out of this, and,
uh, the kid really did knife his father. Huh?
Are you ready?
Hup.
That one.
Sorry, blue eyes.
- Well, where else -
- Okay, fellas, let's take our seats.
Looks like we'll be here
for dinner, huh?
Okay, now let's -
Let's get down to business.
Now, who wants to start it off?
- I would.
- Okay, go.
You down there.
The old man who lived downstairs says he
heard the kid yell out, "I'm gonna kill ya."
A second later,
he heard the body hit the floor.
Now, he ran to the door and he saw the kid
running down the stairs and out of the house.
What does that mean to you?
I was wondering how clearly the old man could
have heard the boy's voice through the ceiling.
He didn't hear it through the ceiling.
The window was open.
So was the one upstairs.
It was a hot night, remember?
Well, it was another apartment.
It's not that easy to identify a voice,
particularly a shouting voice.
- He identified it in court.
- That's right.
And don't forget the lady
across the street.
She looked right in the open window
and saw the boy stab his father.
- Now, I mean, isn't that enough for you?
- No, it isn't.
Boy, how do you like this guy, huh?
It's like talking into a dead phone.
She said she saw the killing through the
windows of a moving elevated train.
There were six cars on the train.
She saw the killing through the last two cars.
She remembered
the most insignificant details.
I don't see how you can argue with that.
Has anybody here any idea
how long it would take an el...
Hey!
This isn't a game.
- Did you see him?
- Hey.
- The nerve.
- All right, listen...
- The absolute nerve.
- Forget it. It's not important.
- "This isn't a game"?
- Calm down.
- Who does he think he is?
- I'm telling you, forget it now.
Has anybody any idea how long
it takes an elevated train...
going at medium speed
to pass a given point?
- What has that to do with anything?
- How long? Take a guess.
- I wouldn't have the slightest idea.
- What do you think?
I don't know. Maybe 10, 12 seconds?
I think that's a pretty good guess.
Anyone else?
- That sounds right to me.
- Come on. What's the guessing game for?
- What do you say?
- Ten seconds is about right.
All right. Say 10 seconds.
What are you getting at?
This. It takes a six-car el train
10 seconds to pass a given point.
Now let's say the given point is the open window
of the room where the killing took place.
You can reach out of that window
and almost touch the el tracks, right?
Now let me ask you this.
Has anyone here
ever lived near the el tracks?
Well, uh, I just finished painting an
apartment that overlooked an el line.
- I was there for three days.
- What was it like?
- What do you mean?
- Noisy?
Oh, brother. Don't matter though.
We were all punchy.
I lived in a second-floor apartment
near the el line once.
When the window was open and the train
goes by, the noise is almost unbearable.
- You can hardly hear yourself think.
- All right, you can't hear yourself think.
- Will you get to the point?
- I will. Now just a minute.
Let's take two pieces of testimony
and try to put them together.
First. The old man in the
apartment downstairs.
He says he heard the boy say
"I'm gonna kill you"...
and a split second later
heard a body hit the floor.
- One second later, right?
- That's right.
Second. The woman across the street swore
positively she looked out of the window...
and saw the killing through the last two
cars of the passing elevated train, right?
- The last two cars.
- What are you giving us here?
Now, just a minute.
We've agreed that it takes 10 seconds
for a train to pass a given point.
Since the woman saw the killing
through the last two cars...
we can assume that the body
hit the floor just as the train went by.
Therefore, the train had been roaring
by the old man's window...
a full 10 seconds
before the body hit the floor.
The old man,
according to his own testimony...
"I'm gonna kill you," body hitting
the floor a split second later...
would have had to hear the boy
make this statement...
with the el roaring past his nose.
It's not possible he could've heard it.
- That's idiotic. Of course he heard it.
- Do you think he could've heard it?
He said he yelled at the top of his voice.
That's good enough for me.
Even if he heard something, he still
couldn't have identified the voice.
With the el roaring by?
You're talking about a matter of seconds!
Nobody can be that accurate.
I think testimony that could put a boy into
the electric chair should be that accurate.
You know something?
I don't think he could've heard it.
Maybe he didn't hear it.
I mean, with all that el noise.
Oh, what are you people talking about?
Well, it stands to reason
he couldn't have heard it.
Why should he lie?
What's he got to gain?
Attention maybe.
You keep coming in
with these bright sayings!
Why don't you send 'em in to a paper?
They pay three dollars apiece.
What are you talking to him
like that for?
Guy talks like that to an old man
really ought to get stepped on, you know?
You ought to have more respect, mister.
If you say stuff like that to him again,
I'm gonna lay you out.
Now you go ahead.
You - You say anything you like.
Why do you think
the old man might lie?
It was just that I looked at him
for a very long time.
The seams of his jacket was split,
under the shoulder.
Or did you notice that?
I mean, to come to court like that.
Why...
He was a very old man
in a torn jacket.
And he walked very slowly
to the stand.
He was dragging his left leg
and trying to hide it...
because he was ashamed.
I think I know this man
better than anyone here.
This is a quiet, frightened,
insignificant old man who...
who has been nothing all his life...
who has never had recognition...
or his name in the newspapers.
Nobody knows him.
Nobody quotes him.
Nobody seeks his advice after 75 years.
Gentlemen, that's a very sad thing -
to be nothing.
A man like this needs to be quoted,
to be listened to.
To be quoted just once.
Very important to him.
It would be so hard for him
to recede into the background...
- Wait a minute.
- When there was a chance...
What are you trying to do - tell us he'd
lie just so he could be important once?
No. He wouldn't really lie.
But perhaps he made himself believe
he heard those words...
and recognized the boy's face.
That's the most fantastic story
I've ever heard.
How can you make up a thing like that?
What do you know about it?
Oh, uh, does anybody
want a cough drop?
- No, thanks.
- I'll take one.
You can say what you like. I still don't
see how anybody can think he's not guilty.
There's something else
I'd like to talk about for a minute.
Thanks.
I think we've proved that the old man couldn't
have heard the boy say "I'm gonna kill you."
- But supposing -
- You didn't prove it at all.
- What are you talking about?
- Supposing he really did hear it.
This phrase, how many times
have all of us used it?
Probably thousands.
"I could kill you for that, darling."
"Junior, you do that once more,
and I'm gonna kill you."
"Get in there, Rocky, and kill him."
We say it every day. That doesn't mean
we're really gonna kill anybody.
Wait a minute.
What are you trying to give us here?
The phrase was "I'm gonna kill you."
The kid yelled it at the top of his lungs.
Don't tell me he didn't mean it.
Anybody says a thing like that
the way he said it, they mean it.
Well, gee, now I don't know.
I remember I was arguing with a guy I work
next to at the bank a couple weeks ago.
He called me an idiot, so I yelled at him.
Now listen! This guy's trying to make you
believe things that aren't so.
The kid said he was gonna kill him,
and he did kill him.
Let me ask you this. Do you really think the
boy would shout out a thing like that...
so the whole neighborhood could hear him?
I don't think so.
He's much too bright for that.
Bright? He's a common ignorant slob.
He don't even speak good English.
"He doesn't even speak good English."
Mr. Foreman, I'd like
to change my vote to not guilty.
You what?
- You heard me.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
The vote is nine to three,
favor of guilty.
Well, if this isn't the living end. Huh?
What are you basing it on -
the stories this guy made up?
You ought to write for one of those
kooky detective magazines.
You'd make a fortune.
For crying out loud. The kid's own lawyer
knew he didn't stand a chance.
Right from the beginning,
his own lawyer knew it.
You could see it.
Boy, oh, boy. I'm tellin' you,
this guy here is really something.
Look, the kid had a lawyer, didn't he?
He presented his case, not you.
How come you got so much to say?
- Look, lawyers aren't infallible, you know.
- Baltimore, please. Huh?
He was court-appointed.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It could mean a lot of things.
It could mean he didn't want the case,
or he resented being appointed.
It's the kind of case
that brings him nothing...
no money, no glory,
not even much chance of winning.
That's not a very promising situation
for a young lawyer.
He'd really have to believe in his client
to put up any kind of a good case...
and, as you pointed out a minute ago,
obviously he didn't.
Of course he didn't. Huh.
Who the heck could?
Except maybe
some guy's mother or somebody. I...
Ah, look.
Will you look at the time, huh?
- Come on. For crying out -
- Pardon me.
- I have made some notes here -
- Notes.
And I would like to -
please, to say something.
- Yeah.
- I have been listening very carefully.
And, uh, it seems to me that this man
has some very good points to make.
From what was presented at the trial,
the boy looks guilty on the surface.
- But maybe if we go deeper?
- Oh, come on, will ya?
There is a question I would like to ask.
Let us assume that the boy
really did commit the murder.
Now, this happened
at 10 minutes after 12:00.
Now, how was he caught by the police?
He came back home, uh, at 3:00 or so...
and he was captured by two detectives
in the hallway of his house.
Now, my question is,
if he really had killed his father...
why would he come back home
three hours later?
Wouldn't he be afraid of being caught?
He came home to get his knife.
It's not nice to go around leaving knives
sticking in people's chests.
- Yeah, especially relatives.
- Yeah.
I don't see anything funny about it.
The boy knew the knife could be identified
as the one he had just bought.
He had to get it before the police did.
But if he knew the knife could be identified,
why did he leave it there in the first place?
Well, I think we can assume
the boy ran out in a state of panic...
after having just killed his father.
When he finally calmed down,
he realized he had left his knife there.
Ah. This then depends
on your definition of panic.
He would have had to be
calm enough to see to it...
that there were no fingerprints
left on the knife.
Now, where did this panic start
and where did it end?
Look, you voted guilty.
What side are ya on?
I don't believe I have to be loyal
to one side or the other.
I'm simply asking questions.
Well, this is just off the top of my head,
but, uh...
well, if I were the boy
and I'd done the stabbing and everything...
I'd take a chance
and go back for the knife.
I'll bet he figured that nobody
had seen him running out...
and that the body wouldn't be discovered
till the next day.
Well, after all,
it was the middle of the night.
I'll bet he'd figured nobody
would find the body till the next day.
Pardon. This is my whole point.
The woman across the street testified that
the moment after she saw the killing...
that is, a moment
after the train went by...
she screamed
and then went to telephone the police.
Now, the boy certainly
must have heard the scream...
so he knew
that somebody saw something.
I just don't think
that he would have gone back.
Two things. One, in his state of panic,
he may not have heard the scream.
Perhaps it wasn't very loud.
Two, if he did hear it, he may not
have connected it with his own act.
Remember, he lived in a neighborhood
where screams were fairly commonplace.
- There's your answer.
- Maybe.
Maybe the boy did kill his father,
didn't hear the scream...
did run out in a panic,
did calm down three hours later...
and come back to get the knife,
risking being caught by the police.
Maybe all of those things happened,
but maybe they didn't.
I think there's enough doubt that we can
wonder whether he was there at all...
during the time the killing took place.
What do you mean doubt?
What are you talking about?
Didn't the old man see him
running out of the house?
He's twisting the facts, I'm telling you.
Did or didn't the old man see the kid
running out of the house at 12:10?
Well, did or didn't he?
- He says he did.
- "Says he did"? Boy! How do you like that?
- Now, look, witnesses can make mistakes.
- Sure, when you want them to, they do.
Or when he wants them to, they do.
You know what I mean?
- Keep the yelling down!
- Oh, you keep saying that.
Maybe what we need
is a little yelling in here.
These guys
keep going off every which way.
Did hear the scream.
Didn't hear the scream.
What difference does it make? You people
are talking only about the little details.
You're forgetting the important stuff.
I mean, all of a sudden, everybody here...
- I want to call for another vote.
- I'm talking here!
There's another vote called for.
Now let's take our seats.
I never saw so much time
spent on nothing.
It only takes a second.
Okay. I guess the fastest way
is to find out who's voting not guilty.
Now, all those voting not guilty,
please raise your hands.
Still the same.
One, two, three not guilty. Nine guilty.
So, now where are we?
I'm telling you, we can yackety-yack until
next Tuesday. Where's it all getting us?
Pardon. I vote not guilty.
Oh!
What are ya talking about? I mean,
we're all going crazy in here or something.
The kid is guilty.
Why don't you listen to the facts?
Tell him, will ya?
Now this is getting to be a joke.
The vote is eight to four,
favor of guilty.
What is this, love your underprivileged
brother week or something?
I want you to get up and tell me
why you changed your vote.
- Come on. Give me your reasons.
- I don't have to defend my decision to you.
There is a reasonable doubt in my mind.
What reasonable doubt? That's nothing but words.
Here, look at this.
The kid you just decided isn't guilty
was seen ramming this into his father.
Now, what about this,
Mr. Reasonable Doubt?
That's not the knife.
Don't you remember?
Oh, brilliant.
I'm telling ya, this is the craziest.
I mean, what are we supposed to believe?
I mean, you're sittin' here, you're pulling
stories out of thin air, you know?
A guy like this, if he's, uh, sitting
ringside at the Dempsey-Firpo fight...
he'd be trying to tell you that, uh...
Look. Now, what about the old man?
Are we supposed to believe that he
didn't get up and run to his door...
and see the kid tearing down the steps
15 seconds after the killing?
He's just saying so to be important, right?
- I mean, what's the point of the whole thing?
- Wait. Hold it a second, will you?
Oh, and the Baltimore rooter
is heard from again now...
and pop-ups are fallin' for base hits
wherever we look.
Hold it a second. Now, look -
Did the old man say he ran to the door?
Ran, walked. What's the difference? He got on, didn't he?
I mean, he got there, didn't he?
- No, now wait a second.
- He said he ran. At least I think he did.
Look, I don't remember what he said, but I
don't see how he could have run to the door.
Ηe said he went
from his bedroom to the front door.
- Now, isn't that enough?
- Where was the bedroom?
- It was down the hall somewhere.
- I thought you remembered everything.
- Don't you remember that?
- No.
Mr. Foreman, I'd like to see
a diagram of the apartment.
- Why don't we just have 'em run the trial all over again
so you can get everything straight? - Mr. Foreman.
How come you're the only one in this room
wants to see exhibits all the time?
- I want to see this one too.
- And I'd like to stop wasting time.
If we're gonna start wading through all that
nonsense about where the body was found...
We're not,
not unless somebody else wants to.
But I'd like to find out if an old man...
who drags one foot when he walks
'cause he had a stroke last year...
can get from his bedroom
to his front door in 15 seconds.
- He said 20 seconds.
- Ηe said 15.
He said 20 seconds.
What are you trying to distort...
- He said 15.
- How does he know how long 15 seconds is?
You can't judge a thing like that.
- He said 15 seconds.
- He was very positive about it.
He was an old man.
Half the time he was confused.
How could he be positive about anything?
I don't see what you're going to prove here.
The man said he saw the boy running out.
Well, let's see
if the details bear him out.
As soon as the body hit the floor,
he said he heard footsteps upstairs...
running toward the front door...
heard the upstairs door open,
the footsteps start down the stairs.
He said he got to his own front door
as fast as he could...
and he swore it couldn't have been
more than 15 seconds.
Now, if the killer
began running immediately...
- Maybe he didn't.
- The old man said he did.
You ought to be at Atlantic City
at that hairsplitters convention.
Hey, why don't you stop makin'
smart remarks all the time, huh?
My friend, for your three dollars a day,
you have to listen to everything, you know?
Now that you've got that thing in here,
what about it?
All right. Here's the apartment
where the killing took place.
The old man's apartment
was directly beneath and exactly the same.
Here are the el tracks, the bedroom,
living room, kitchen, bathroom.
Here's the hall. Here are the stairs.
Now, the old man
was in this bedroom right here.
He says he crossed to the door
and walked down the hall...
opened the front door just in time
to see the boy running down the stairs.
- Am I right so far?
- That's the story, for the 19th time.
- Fifteen seconds after the body hit the floor.
- Correct.
Now, let's see. It was...
It's 12 feet from the bed to the door.
The hall is 43 feet.
He would have had to walk 12 feet,
open the bedroom door...
walk 43 feet down and open the front door
all in 15 seconds.
- Do you think he could have done it?
- Sure he could have done it.
He can walk only very slowly.
They had to help him into the witness chair.
You make it sound like a long walk.
For an old man who had a stroke,
it is a long walk.
- Oh! What are you doing?
- I'm gonna try it, see how long it took him.
What do you mean, you want to try it?
Why didn't his lawyer bring it up if it's so important?
- Maybe he just didn't think about it, huh?
- What do you mean, didn't think of it? You think the man's an idiot or something?
- It's an obvious thing.
- Did you think of it?
Listen, smart guy.
Don't matter whether I thought of it.
He didn't bring it up because he knew it would
hurt his case. What do you think of that?
Maybe he didn't bring it up because it would have
meant bullying and badgering a helpless old man.
You know that doesn't sit very well with a jury.
Most lawyers avoid it if they can.
- So, what kind of a bum is he then?
- That's what I've been asking, buddy.
Pass me that chair, will you?
Those two chairs are the old man's bed.
I just paced off 12 feet across the room.
This will be the bedroom door.
Oh, that's crazy.
You can't recreate a thing like that.
- I'd like to see it.
- The hall was 43 feet.
I'll pace from that wall and back again.
Look, this is absolutely insane.
What are you wasting everybody's time in here for?
According to you, it'll only take 15 seconds.
Now, we can spare that, see.
Come on. Knock it off.
Okay.
Okay. Okay, killer.
Yeah.
Will you stand right there
and mark the front door?
It was chain-locked according
to the testimony, remember?
- Has anybody got a watch with a second hand?
- I have.
When you want me to start, stamp your foot.
That'll be the body falling.
You can time me from there.
What are we gonna do, play charades now?
- Come on! What are we waiting for?
- Okay, I'm ready.
Well, I want to wait
till the second hand reaches 60.
Oh, come on.
Come on. Speed it up.
He could walk twice as fast as that.
You want me to walk faster than that,
I will.
Lock. Door. Stop.
- Right.
- What's the time?
Uh, exactly 41 seconds.
This is what I think happened.
The old man heard the fight between the boy
and his father a few hours earlier.
Then when he's lying in bed, he heard the
body hit the floor in the boy's apartment...
heard the woman scream from across the street,
got to his front door as fast as he could...
heard somebody racing down the stairs
and assumed it was the boy.
- I think that's possible.
- Assumed?
Oh.
Brother, I've seen all kinds of dishonesty in
my day, but this little display takes the cake.
You all come in here with your hearts bleeding all
over the floor about slum kids and injustice.
You listen to some fairy tales.
Suddenly you start getting through
to some of these old ladies.
Well, you're not getting through to me.
I've had enough.
What's the matter with you guys?
You all know he's guilty!
He's got to burn!
You're letting him slip
through our fingers.
"Slip through our fingers"?
Are you his executioner?
I'm one of 'em!
Perhaps you'd like to pull the switch.
For this kid, you bet I would.
I feel sorry for you. What it must
feel like to want to pull the switch.
Ever since you walked into this room, you've been
acting like a self-appointed public avenger.
You want to see this boy die because you
personally want it, not because of the facts.
- You're a sadist.
- You...
Let me go!
I'll kill him. I'll kill him!
You don't really mean
you'll kill me, do you?
Is there anything wrong, gentlemen?
I heard some noise.
Oh, no. Everything's all right. We're just
- You know, friendly little argument. It's...
Um, listen, we're through with that diagram.
You can take it if you want.
Here you are. Thank you.
What are you lookin' at?
I suppose somebody
has to start it off again.
- I beg pardon.
- "I beg pardon." What are you so polite about?
For the same reason you're not.
It's the way I was brought up.
This fighting...
That's not why we are here, to fight.
We have a responsibility.
This, I have always thought,
is a remarkable thing about democracy...
that we are...
Uh, what is the word?
Notified.
That we are notified by mail...
to come down to this place
to decide on the guilt or innocence...
of a man we have never heard of before.
We have nothing to gain or lose
by - by our verdict.
This is one of the reasons
why we are strong.
We should not make it a personal thing.
Thank you.
If nobody else has an idea,
I may have a cutie here.
I mean, I haven't given it much thought,
but let's throw it out on the stoop...
and see if the cat licks it up.
- The cat licks it up?
- Yeah. If the boy...
Look how dark it's getting out there.
I'll bet we're gonna have a storm now.
Boy, oh, boy. It's really hot, huh?
Pardon me, but don't you ever sweat?
No, I don't.
Well, listen. I, uh...
I was wondering if, uh, maybe...
maybe we should take another vote.
Oh, great. Maybe we can follow this one up
with a little dancing and refreshments, huh?
- Hmm.
- Mr. Foreman?
Well, that's okay with me.
Anyone doesn't want to vote?
- Hey, come on. Come on.
- I'm sorry.
I think we ought to have an open ballot -
call out our votes, you know.
Let's see who stands where.
That sounds fair to me.
Anyone object?
Okay. I'll call off your jury numbers.
One.
Oh, that's me. I vote guilty.
Two?
Not guilty.
- Number three?
- Guilty.
Number four?
Guilty.
- Number five?
- Not guilty.
- Number six?
Number seven?
Guilty.
Number eight?
Not guilty.
- Number nine?
- Not guilty.
- Number 10?
- Guilty.
Number 11?
Not guilty.
Number 12?
Number 12.
Guilty.
The vote is now six to six.
Yeah, right.
And we go into extra innings here, huh?
Six to six. I'm telling you, some of you
people in here must be out of your minds.
A kid like that.
I don't think the kind of boy he is
has anything to do with it.
The facts are supposed
to determine the case.
Don't give me that!
I'm sick and tired of facts!
You can twist them any way you like.
You know what I mean?
That's exactly the point
this gentleman has been making.
- Oh!
- I mean, you keep shouting at the top of your lungs.
I'd like to be a few years younger.
That man gets on my...
- My, it's hot in here, isn't it?
- Do you want a drink of water?
No. No, thanks. Thanks.
It's gonna rain.
Well, how'd you figure that out, killer?
How come you changed your vote?
Well, it just seemed to me
there was room for doubt.
You haven't got a leg to stand on.
You know that, I hope.
I don't feel that way.
There were a lot of details that never came out.
- Yeah. Well, good luck.
- Oh, come on. You're like everybody else.
You think too much.
You get mixed up.
- You know what I mean?
- Now, listen. I don't think you have any right...
Loudmouth.
Look at that come down, will you?
You know...
this reminds me of a storm we had last...
Oh, when was that? November...
I don't know. Something.
It was quite a storm we had there.
It was right in the middle of a game.
Uh, we were behind 7-6...
but we just started to move the ball,
right off the tackle.
Started cutting right -
slash here and slash right in...
cut right through.
And, uh...
We had this kid Slattery, you know?
A real - He was an ox.
You know, a real ox.
I wish I had another one just like him.
I forgot to tell you. I'm the assistant head
coach at the Andrew J. McCorkle High School.
- Oh, yeah?
- That's out in Queens.
And, uh, anyway...
we're starting to move along real nice.
Their whole line is just -
they're just coming apart.
And it starts to come down
cats and dogs, just like this.
Just whoosh - you know, right down.
Well, that was murder, you know?
I swear, I - I nearly bawled.
You just - You couldn't go nowhere.
Well.
Hey, what is it with this fan here?
How come...
Hey! Ηuh?
Must have been
on the same switch with the lights.
Well, things are looking up here, huh?
Yeah, huh?
Boy. That's better.
Hey!
Two points.
Any of you guys ever go to the Garden?
That's a damn stupid thing to do.
Oh, I'm sorry. I, uh...
You know?
Pardon me.
Well, how do you like it?
Even Steven.
Pretty surprising, isn't it?
Yes.
Say, that business before,
when that tall guy - what's-his-name...
was trying to bait me -
That doesn't prove anything.
I'm a pretty excitable person.
I mean, where does he come off calling me
a public avenger, sadist and everything?
Anyone in his right mind
would blow his stack, huh?
He was just trying to bait me.
He did an excellent job.
I'll tell you what I think.
We're going nowhere here.
I'm ready to walk into court right now
and declare a hung jury.
There's no point in this thing
going on any more.
Yeah. I go for that too.
Listen, let's take it in to the judge and let
the kid take his chances with 12 other guys.
I don't think the judge will accept a hung jury.
We haven't been in here very long.
Well, let's find out.
I'm not in favor of that.
Listen. This kid wouldn't stand a chance
with another jury, and you know it.
Come on! We're hung. Nobody's gonna
change his vote. Let's take it inside.
You still don't think there's room
for reasonable doubt?
No, I don't.
Pardon.
Maybe you don't fully understand
the term "reasonable doubt."
What do you mean I don't understand?
Boy, how do ya like this guy?
I'm tellin' ya, they're all alike.
They come over here, running for their life,
and before they can take a deep breath...
they're telling us how
to run the show, huh?
Boy, the arrogance of this guy.
Hey, all right. Let's stop
the arguing for about two minutes in here.
Now, who's got something
constructive to say?
I'd like to go over something,
if you gentlemen don't mind.
An important point for the prosecution
was the fact...
that after the boy claimed
he'd been at the movies...
during the hours
that the killing took place...
couldn't remember the names of the movies
or the stars who appeared in them.
This gentleman here has put up that point
in here several times.
That's correct.
It was the only alibi the boy offered...
and he himself couldn't back it up
with any details at all.
Putting yourself in the boy's place,
do you think you could remember details...
after an upsetting experience such as
being slapped in the face by your father?
I think so, if there were
any special details to remember.
The boy couldn't remember the names of the movies
he saw because be wasn't there that night.
According to
the police testimony in court...
the boy was questioned by the detectives
in the kitchen of his apartment...
while the body of his father
was lying on the floor in the bedroom.
Do you think you could remember details
under those circumstances?
- I do.
- Under great emotional stress?
- Under great emotional stress.
- He remembered them correctly in court.
He named the pictures
and the stars who played in them.
Yes. His lawyer took great pains
to bring that out.
He had three months from the night
of the murder to the day of the trial...
in which to memorize them.
It's not difficult for a lawyer to find out
what played at a particular theater...
on a particular night.
I'll take the testimony of the policemen who
interrogated the boy right after the murder...
when he couldn't remember
a thing about the movies...
great emotional stress or not.
- I'd like to ask you a personal question.
- Go ahead.
- Where were you last night?
- I was home.
- How about the night before that?
- Come on! What is this?
No, it's all right.
I left the office at 8:30
and went straight home and to bed.
And the night before that?
That was, uh, Tuesday night?
The night of the bridge tournament.
I played bridge.
Monday night?
When you get down
to New Year's Eve, 1954, let me know, huh?
Monday night?
Monday night, uh,
my wife and I went to the movies.
- What did you see?
- The Scarlet Circle.
- It was a clever whodunit.
- What was the second feature?
The, um...
I'll tell you in a minute. The, uh...
Remarkable Mrs., uh, something...
The...
Mrs. Bainbridge.
The Remarkable Mrs. Bainbridge.
I saw that.
It's called The Amazing Mrs. Bainbridge.
Uh, yes. The Amazing Mrs. Bainbridge.
I think that's right.
Who was in The Amazing Mrs. Bainbridge?
Barbara... Long, I think it was.
A dark, very pretty girl.
Ling or Long - something like that.
- Who else?
- I'd never heard of them before.
It was a very inexpensive second feature
with, uh, unknown...
And you weren't under
an emotional stress, were you?
No.
I wasn't.
I think the point is made.
Big point!
You can talk till your tongue
is draggin' on the floor.
The boy is guilty, period.
You know what I mean, my friend?
- Who's got those cough drops?
- They're all gone, my friend.
Oh, boy. Look at that rain.
There goes your ball game.
It's only a shower.
Besides, they got the infield covered.
Right. Say, could I see that knife
a second, please?
Well, we're still tied up six to six.
Who's got a suggestion?
It's five after 6:00.
Let's get some dinner.
Why don't we wait till 7:00,
give it another hour, huh?
Okay with me.
Uh, there's something I'd like to say.
I mean, it's been bothering me a little,
and as long as we're stuck.
Well, there was this whole business
about the stab wound and how it was made...
the downward angle of it, you know?
Don't tell me we're gonna
start with that again.
They've been over it and over it.
Well, I know they did,
but I don't go along with it.
Now, the boy was 5 feet 7 inches tall.
His father was 6'2...
That's a difference of seven inches.
It's a very awkward thing to stab down
into the chest of someone...
who's more than half a foot
taller than you are.
Give me that.
I'll give you a demonstration.
Somebody get up.
You...
I want you to watch this 'cause
I don't want to have to do it again.
I'll make myself about six
or seven inches shorter, okay?
- It's about right. Maybe a little more.
- Okay. A little more.
That's not funny.
Now, nobody's hurt. Right?
Right. Nobody hurt.
Now, this is the way I'd stab a man
who was taller than I was.
Look at the angle - down and in.
And this is the way it was done.
Now tell me I'm wrong.
- Down and in. I guess there's no argument.
- Hold it a minute, will ya?
Can you give me that?
Boy, I hate these things.
- Did you ever see a knife fight?
- No.
- You?
Anybody here ever see a knife fight?
Well, I have.
You know, on my back stoop...
the lot across the street, backyard.
Switchblades came
with the neighborhood where I lived.
It's funny I never thought of it before.
I guess you try to forget those things.
- How do you use a switchblade?
- Well, you'd never use it like this.
See, you use too much time
switching hands.
Here's how - underhanded.
Anyone who's ever used a switch knife
wouldn't handle it any other way.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
That's why they're made to open like that.
- You'd say the boy was pretty handy with a knife?
- Mm-hmm.
You think he could have made
the kind of wound that killed his father?
No. Not with the experience he'd had
all his life handling these things.
I feel he'd have gone for him underhanded.
How do you know? Were you
in the room when the father was killed?
No. Neither was anybody else.
So what are you giving us all this
mumbo jumbo for? I don't believe it.
I don't think you can determine what type of
wound the boy might or might not have made...
simply because he knew
how to handle a knife.
What do you think?
- I don't know.
- What do you mean you don't know?
I don't know.
How about you?
I don't know about the rest of them, but I'm getting a
little tired of this yackety-yackin' back and forth.
It's gettin' us nowhere.
So I guess I'll have to break it up.
I change my vote to not guilty.
- You what?
- You heard me. I've had enough.
What do you mean you've had enough?
That's no answer!
Hey, listen. You just take care
of yourself, huh? You know?
He's right. That's not an answer.
What kind of a man are you?
You have sat here and voted guilty
with everyone else...
because there are some baseball tickets
burning a hole in your pocket.
And now you've changed your vote because you
say you're sick of all the talking here?
Now listen, buddy!
Who tells you that you have the right
to play like this with a man's life?
- Don't you care -
- Now wait a minute!
- You can't talk like that to me!
- I can talk like that to you.
If you want to vote not guilty...
then do it because you are convinced
the man is not guilty...
not because you've had enough.
And if you think he is guilty,
then vote that way.
Or don't you have the guts
to do what you think is right?
- Now listen.
- Guilty or not guilty?
- I told you, not guilty.
- Why?
Look, I don't have to...
You do have to! Say it! Why?
All right. I don't, uh, think he's guilty.
I want another vote.
Okay. There's another vote called for.
I guess the quickest way is a show of hands.
Anyone object?
Okay. All those voting not guilty,
raise your hands.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
eight.
Um, nine.
Um, all those voting guilty,
raise your hands.
One, two, three.
Well, the vote's nine to three
in favor of acquittal.
I don't understand you people!
I mean, all these picky little points
you keep bringing up.
They don't mean nothing!
You saw this kid just like I did.
You're not gonna tell me you believe
that phony story about losing the knife...
and that business
about being at the movies.
Look, you know how these people lie.
It's born in them.
I mean, what the heck.
I don't have to tell you.
They don't know what the truth is.
And let me tell you, they don't need
any real big reason to kill someone either.
No, sir.
They get drunk!
Oh, they're real big drinkers, all of 'em.
You know that.
And bang - someone's lying in the gutter.
Well, nobody's blaming them for it.
That's the way they are, by nature.
You know what I mean? Violent!
Where are you going?
Ηuman life don't mean
as much to them as it does to us.
Look! They're lushing it up
and fighting all the time...
and if somebody gets killed,
so somebody gets killed!
They don't care!
Oh, sure, there's some good things
about 'em too.
Look, I'm the first one to say that.
I've known a couple who were okay, but
that's the exception, you know what I mean?
Most of 'em, it's like they have no feelings.
They can do anything.
What's going on here?
I'm - I'm trying to tell ya...
you're making a big mistake, you people.
This kid is a liar!
I know it. I know all about them.
Listen to me.
They're no good.
There's not a one of 'em who's any good.
I mean, what -
What's happening in here?
I'm speaking my piece, and you...
Listen to me.
I...
We're - This kid on trial here, his type...
Well, don't you know about them?
Th-There's - There's a danger here.
These people are dangerous.
They're... wild.
Listen to me.
- Listen.
- I have.
Now sit down
and don't open your mouth again.
I was only trying to... tell you.
It's always difficult to keep personal
prejudice out of a thing like this.
Wherever you run into it,
prejudice always obscures the truth.
I don't really know what the truth is.
I don't suppose anybody
will ever really know.
Nine of us now seem to feel
that the defendant is innocent.
But we're just gambling on probabilities.
We may be wrong.
We may be trying to let
a guilty man go free.
I don't know.
Nobody really can.
But we have a reasonable doubt...
and that's something
that's very valuable in our system.
No jury can declare a man guilty
unless it's sure.
We nine can't understand...
how you three are still so sure.
- Maybe you can tell us.
- I'll try.
You've made some excellent points, but I
still believe the boy is guilty of murder...
and I have two reasons.
One, the evidence
given by the woman across the street...
who actually saw the murder committed.
As far as I'm concerned,
that's the most important testimony.
And two, the fact that she
described the stabbing by saying...
she saw the boy raise his arm over his head
and stab down into the father's chest.
She saw him do it the wrong way.
That's absolutely right.
Let's talk about this woman for a moment.
She said she went to bed
about 11:00 that night.
Her bed was next to the window,
and she could look out while lying down...
and see directly into the boy's room
across the street.
She tossed and turned for over an hour,
unable to sleep.
Finally, she turned toward the window
at about 10 minutes after 12:00...
and, as she looked out, she saw the killing
through the windows of a passing el train.
She said the lights went out
immediately after the killing...
but that she got a good look at the boy
in the act of stabbing his father.
As far as I can see it,
this is unshakable testimony.
- Well, that's the whole case.
- What do you think?
How about you?
I-I don't know.
So much evidence to sift.
This is a pretty complicated business.
Frankly, I don't see
how you can vote for acquittal.
It's not so easy to arrange
all the evidence in order.
You can throw out
all the other evidence!
The woman saw him do it!
What else do you want?
- Yeah, well, maybe -
- Let's vote on it.
Okay. There's another vote called for.
Anybody object?
All right. I'm changing my vote.
He's guilty.
Anybody else?
The vote is eight to four.
Why is this such a personal triumph
for you - this one vote?
Okay. I say we're a hung jury.
I say we take it in to the judge.
Ηow about it?
I want to hear arguments.
You, you're the leader of the cause.
What about it?
Let's go over it again.
We've been over it again!
The boy in the gray flannel suit here is bouncin'
backwards and forwards like a tennis ball.
No point in getting nasty
and trying to turn this into a contest.
Okay.
Maybe we can talk about
setting some kind of time limit.
Yeah, once around for the deal, huh?
It's a quarter after 6:00.
Someone before mentioned 7:00.
I think that's a point at which
we might begin to discuss...
the question of whether
we're a hung jury or not.
Don't you feel well?
I feel perfectly well, thank you.
I was saying that 7:00
would be a reasonable time.
Uh, the reason I asked about that
was because, uh...
you were rubbing your nose like...
Oh, I'm sorry for interrupting...
but you made a gesture
that reminded me of something.
I'm trying to settle something here.
Do you mind?
Well, I think this is important.
Thank you.
Now then,
I'm sure you'll pardon me for this...
but I was wondering why
you were rubbing your nose like that.
Oh, come on, will ya?
At this point, I happen to be talking
to the gentleman sitting next to you!
Now, why were you rubbing
your nose like that?
Well, if it's any of your business, I was
rubbing it because it bothers me a little.
Oh. I'm sorry.
- Is it - Is it because of your eyeglasses?
- It is.
Now can we get on to something else?
Your eyeglasses made those two
deep impressions on the sides of your nose.
I hadn't noticed that before.
- That must be annoying.
- It is very annoying.
Well, I wouldn't know about that.
I've never worn eyeglasses.
Twenty-twenty.
Listen, will you come on already
with the optometrist bit?
The woman who testified
that she saw the killing...
had those same marks
on the sides of her nose.
Holy smokes! You know, he's right.
Please.
Just give me a minute,
and I'll be finished.
I don't know if anyone else
noticed that about her.
I didn't think of it then,
but I've been going over her face...
in my mind.
She had those same marks.
- She kept rubbing them in court.
- He's right. She did do that a lot.
This woman was about, uh -
about 45 years old.
She was making a tremendous effort
to look 35...
for her first public appearance.
Heavy makeup, dyed hair...
brand-new clothes that should have
been worn by a younger woman.
No glasses.
No, women do that.
See if you can get the
mental picture of it.
What do you mean, no glasses?
How do you know whether she wore glasses?
Just 'cause she was rubbing her nose?
Now, she had those marks. I saw 'em.
So what?
What do ya think that means?
- Listen, I'm getting so sick of your yelling in here!
- Come on. Forget it.
Hey, listen. Listen, he's right.
I saw them too.
I was the closest one to her. She had these,
uh - these things on the side of her nose.
- What do you call those on the side?
- Well, what point are you making here?
She had dyed hair, marks on her nose.
Well, what does that mean?
Could those marks be made
by anything other than eyeglasses?
No, they couldn't.
I didn't see any marks!
I did.
Strange, but I didn't
think about it before.
Well, what about the lawyer?
Why didn't he say something?
There are 12 people in here
concentrating on this case.
Eleven of us didn't think of it either.
Well, what about the district attorney?
Do you think he'd pull a trick like that?
Have her testify without her glasses?
Did you ever see a woman who had to wear glasses and
didn't want to because she thinks they spoil her looks?
Okay. She had marks on her nose.
I'm giving you that.
From glasses, right?
She didn't want to wear 'em out of the house
so people would think she's gorgeous.
But when she saw this kid killing his
father, she was in the house alone.
That's all.
- Do you wear glasses when you go to bed?
- No, I don't.
No one wears eyeglasses to bed.
It's logical to assume that she wasn't
wearing them when she was in bed...
tossing and turning, trying to fall asleep.
- How do you know?
- I don't know! I'm guessing.
I'm also guessing that she probably
didn't put her glasses on...
when she turned
to look casually out of the window.
And she herself testified the killing
took place just as she looked out.
The lights went off a split second later.
She couldn't have had time to put them on then.
- Wait a second.
- Here's another guess.
Maybe she honestly thought she saw the boy
kill his father. I say she only saw a blur.
How do you know what she saw?
How does he know all that?
How do you know what kind of glasses she wore?
Maybe they were sunglasses.
Maybe she was farsighted.
What do you know about it?
I only know the woman's eyesight
is in question now.
She had to be able to identify a person
60 feet away, at night, without glasses.
You can't send someone off to die
on evidence like that.
Oh, don't give me that.
Don't you think the woman
might have made a mistake?
- No.
- It's not possible?
No, it's not possible.
Is it possible?
Not guilty.
Do you think he's guilty?
I think he's guilty.
Do you?
No. I'm convinced.
Not guilty.
What's the matter with you?
I have a reasonable doubt now.
Eleven to one.
Well, what about all the other evidence?
What about all that stuff?
The knife, the whole business!
Well, you said we could throw out
all the other evidence.
Well, what do we do now?
You're alone.
I don't care whether I'm alone or not!
It's my right.
It's your right.
Well, what do you want?
I say he's guilty.
- We want to hear your arguments.
- I gave you my arguments.
We're not convinced.
We want to hear them again.
We have as much time as it takes.
Everything - Every single thing
that took place in that courtroom...
but I mean everything -
says he's guilty.
What do you think,
I'm an idiot or something?
Why don't you take that stuff
about the old man?
The old man who lived there
and heard everything.
Or this business about the knife.
What? 'Cause he found another one
exactly like it?
The old man saw him
right there on the stairs!
What's the difference
how many seconds it was?
Every single thing.
The knife falling through
a hole in his pocket.
You can't prove he didn't get to the door.
Sure, you can take all the time,
hobble around the room.
But you can't prove it!
And what about this business
of the el and the movies?
There's a phony deal
if I ever heard one.
I'll bet ya $5,000
I'd remember the movies I saw.
I'm telling ya,
everything that's gone on...
has been twisted and turned!
This business with the glasses?
How do you know she didn't have them on?
This woman testified in open court!
And what about hearing the kid yell, huh?
I'm telling ya, I've got
all the facts here.
Here. Ah...
Well, that's it!
That's the whole case.
Well?
Say something!
You lousy bunch of bleeding hearts.
You're not gonna intimidate me.
I'm entitled to my opinion.
Rotten kids.
You work your life out!
I can't keep...
No.
Not guilty.
Not...
Um, we're ready now.
Hey!
What's your name?
Davis.
My name's McCardle.
Well, so long.
So long.